Hey there, welcome back to
Intermediate ASP.NET Core.
My name is Jeff Fritz.
>> And I'm Jon Galloway.
>> And
we're gonna talk to you for
a little bit about tag
helpers in this module.
Jon, we've been hearing
a lot about tag helpers.
What the heck are tag helpers?
>> I think tag
helpers are great.
The cool thing with tag
helpers is they kind of get
out of your way.
>> So they make it easier for
me to write markup,
the HTML looking markup that's
doing stuff on my server.
And it's very lightweight.
>> Mm.
>> So it kind of almost,
you know,
it's nice to know about but
for the most part it just kind
of fades into the background.
But we'll be showing how
you'll be using tag helpers in
a file new project.
We'll dig into a little bit of
writing our own tag helper.
>> Okay.
>> Which is
really easy actually.
And then after we've done that
we'll look at some third party
tag helpers, some things that
other developers have written
that I can start using.
And we'll look at
their search code too.
>> Cool.
>> So let's get started,
if we can go to my screen.
We're going to be
working off of the docs.
So everything I'm going
to be showing here is in
the docs at docs.microsoft.com.
So, this starts off with
a simple, what is a tag helper?
Hopefully, this says something
pretty similar to what I just
explained.
Things like this, HTML
friendly developer experience,
giving me IntelliSense etcetera.
And then we're gonna be
showing authoring tag helpers,
that's written up in here.
So if I'm talking too fast or
not making sense,
you can read the docs and
that's gonna work well for you.
[LAUGH] So I'm gonna start
with Web application 24.
This is literally
file new project.
>> It's so much better than
web applications 1 through 20.
>> Those ones, throw them away.
>> They're garbage.
>> We're gonna ship this.
>> Modern new, all right.
>> What I need you to do
while I'm talking is if you
an register webapplication24.com
.edu and .org.
>> I'm on it.
>> Because this is it,
we're gonna IPO.
So I've gone through and
I've done file new project,
literally that's it.
And I did this using, I turned
on individual authentication.
I did that partly because I want
to show off some things that
are in the account
management system.
Because this is a great
example of where tag
helpers can simplify my markup.
So I'm going to be looking in
this manage directory to start.
>> Okay.
>> So this is stuff for
when I've created,
I wanna register in a user.
So I got into
the register page and
you'll see some things in here
that some kind of purple markup.
So they look similar to
the other things but
here like this form,
if we look at that, that has a,
it's kind of purplish and-
>> It's also bold for
anybody who's color blind so
they can see it as well.
>> That's nice, right?
And you can go in and
change these too, by the way.
>> Absolutely.
>> You can go in and
set those differently.
And as I mouse over this,
this shows some things that
are different like
here this is just HTML.
This just says it's
a div element.
>> Great.
>> It's very, very simple.
IntelSense for form actually
says this is related to a form,
and if I mouse over this
asp-route-returnUrl, that
actually tells me, this is a
generic IDictionary and it also
explains some things, additional
parameters for our route.
>> I didn't know HTML could
handle IDictionaries.
>> Aha, see and it can't, right?
So that's an important thing
that you've called out there.
Is that these things, this is
not the HTML that's gonna be
rendered out to the browser.
So in fact, if I just run this,
we'll look at,
if we look at I guess I
can go to register and
we could just view source,
right?
>> Sure.
>> See and I'm already going off
script, but that's just fine.
Yes, let's install, so
I recommend, I was gonna joke
about installing any certificate
that requests to install, but
that's probably bad advice.
In this case though, this is
actually, this is a it's setting
up an SSL search and
trusting it locally so
I can develop against
HTTPS which is cool.
>> Right, this is a Visual
Studio feature that allows
us to use SSL.
>> Yep so here I'm
clicking on register, and
this is exactly that same thing
I was looking at before, and
if I go in and view source, and
if we look at that form, we'll
find that form is rendered.
>> There's our nav bar,
there's form, form right.
>> So
if we zoom in on that we'll see
that form says method post
action is Account/Register.
>> That's a normal
HTML form there.
>> That's normal,
this is straight up HTML, right?
But if we flip over to here,
you'll see.
This is what we've
got in my Razor code.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Method is post,
it didn't change that, but this
ReturnUrl where this is gonna be
posted to, that is something
that the server asp.net,
looked at this and converted it
to action = /Account/Register.
>> Okay.
>> So
what's important about that is,
where this form is being
posted to could change
based on how my
routing is set up.
>> Sure.
>> Based on if this is,
if I'm using the NBC route or
if I'm going in and
changing my routes,
that could vary.
>> Okay.
>> So other things here like as
we look further down in this,
we've got label
asp-for="Input.Email".
So this is using my input model,
and we've seen about
models in some previous
sessions and all that.
So this is using my e-mail
field on my input model and
it's saying binds to that.
If we look at what we're
actually seeing on these,
this is saying which
control is it even?
Data val email.
>> Is that it on line 53?
>> 53, there you go, so it's
Input_Email let me zoom on that.
So that is here, Input_Email,
or some people say underbar,
either one works, right?
>> Sure.
>> So
the important thing
is if I change that,
I could make a change
to that in my model and
again it's going to
figure out that for me.
So the nice thing that we're
seeing with this, is that we're
able to write server-side
code inside our Razor code,
and we can do it in a way
that still is readable here,
it's not kind of
jumping back and forth.
>> So that label tag
helper you showed us,
it says asp-for="Input.Email",
so
it's looking at that email
property and it's going to
figure out what type of label to
generate based on that property.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
>> So
it's generating
HTML based on that.
So the important things
we've learned so
far is that bold purple
means that is a tag helper.
>> Okay.
>> And that is going to evaluate
something on the server and
probably change the HTML,
and if I see something that's
an asp-, that is probably not
gonna be, it's not gonna
render that on the client.
The clients aren't
gonna see asp- but
they're gonna possibly see some
other HTML that's generated.
>> Okay.
>> So we've learned that and
that's interesting.
We're looking here at a div tag
helper and a form tag helper.
There are other tag
helpers that don't even
match up to anything in HTML.
>> So those ones were tag
helpers that were actually
attributes.
>> Yes.
>> That decorated
different elements.
>> Exactly.
These are tag helpers that
work at a higher level.
This is, for instance,
an environment tag helper.
>> So there is no
environment tag in HTML5.
>> Right, and when we run this,
if you looked in there,
you would not see any of this.
There's no HTML output.
Well, there kind of is.
Here I guess I need
to run it again.
So, what this is solving for
me is when I'm running locally-
>> Uh-huh.
>> I wanna pull my CSS like
directly off my file system.
>> Sure.
>> When I'm running in
production however I wanna try
to, We put those
files after CDN.
And that includes the CSS here,
up to the top of the page and
then also way down the bottom,
my JavaScript as well.
We've got matching
environment text down there,
[CROSSTALK] development and
production.
>> And we learned in our
previous module all about
the different environments
that folks can configure.
By default, they get development
when they're in Visual Studio,
if they don't define
an environment,
they get production.
So I'm guessing that the second
environment tag on 54 where it
says, exclude development,
that's how those CDN references
are gonna be used
in Visual Studio.
>> Exactly, so
what this is saying is when I'm
running locally, it's gonna say,
yeah, you're in development and
it's just going to look
directly on my file system and
pull these in.
When I'm running anywhere else,
so production, or
if I define a staging or test or
Jeff's fancy environment.
>> I've got fancy environments,
let me tell you.
>> [LAUGH] It's gonna
use these ones.
>> Okay.
>> And this is actually a nice
feature they just recently
included here in
the 2.0 releases.
This whole include, exclude
that makes it very easy with
the exclude to say
anything except for
development pull these ones in.
>> Gotcha.
>> So I don't even need to know
upfront what they're gonna be
just anything but development.
>> But I can specify multiple
values for that right?
>> Exactly, so I can up here I
could say, include development,
testing, whatever it is, right?
>> Okay.
>> So
now let's take a look
at source for that and
if we look at our CSS,
find our CSS references in here.
>> There they are right there.
>> There they are.
So you'll see this knows that
because we're, It's only
evaluating the environment
tag that's for development.
>> Right, so because
this is development mode,
the development environment,
it only included those
HTML mark up items that were
inside the environment tag.
>> Exactly, so that's that.
>> Now, those tag helpers, they
don't modify anything else on
the rest of the page, do they?
>> So they're generally confined
to that area there, right?
And one interesting thing here
though is that they do kind of
nest.
So you see here we've
got an environment tag,
inside the environment tag,
I've got a script tag.
>> Yeah,
look at that one in purple.
>> And this script tag, this is
doing something interesting.
It's modifying by using
asp-append-version.
So what this does is it solves
a common problem where you have
to version script references.
Otherwise, CDNs or
browsers will just cache
the previous one that I serve.
And I can go in and change my
JavaScript and the browser is
gonna say, I've already got
this one cache locally.
>> So this generates
that cache plaster token.
>> Exactly, so if I go in,
let's take a look at that.
So it depends, I may not
be serving those locally,
I'm not even sure.
I am.
>> There it is.
>> So here if we look at this,
We'll see my site.js has v= and
it's generated a version number.
And that's exactly it,
it's cache bust, right?
So if I go in and
change that JavaScript,
it's going to keep
incrementing that.
So the important thing we've
learned off of that is that
these can be nested.
I can use an environment,
I can put inside the other ones,
and I can use those
to control things.
>> Okay.
>> For any of these,
if I wanna understand
what it's doing,
I've got both IntelliSense
here and I've also got,
if we go back to
these docs here.
It actually has this whole
section here on built-in tag
helpers.
And it's gonna explain,
here is the different tag
helpers that are included and
here's the different kinda
features that are available.
So that's pretty cool,
right off the bat.
Now, another thing that's
neat is I can actually
write my own tag helpers.
Before I show that, I want to
show one last important gotcha,
which is that in order to
reference, in order for these
tag helpers to become active,
they're actually listed in here.
So I try to remember,
sometimes I forget but
this is where these are actually
kind of lit up, right?
So this here,
this Mvc.TagHelpers,
any TagHelpers are kind
of turned on there, cool?
>> So can we look at that
view imports one more time?
>> Yeah.
>> So you have *, and then
Microsoft.AspNetCore.Mvc.TagHel-
pers, that's the assembly
that they leave in.
>> That's the assembly, right.
And I've actually recently,
I made this mistake, right.
I pulled in a namespace or
something else, it's actually
the assembly that's important.
>> So it looks like a normal way
that we would reference a type.
But by using that wild card in
front of the comma, we're saying
give me all those tag helpers
that are in that assembly.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay, got it.
>> So this lights up all the tag
helpers in the MVC assembly.
>> Okay.
>> So let's go an write our
own TagHelper because they're
actually relatively easy.
I'm going to write
a repeat TagHelper and
this is TagHelper that is an
icon nest markup inside it and
it's just going to repeat
it however many times.
Not incredibly useful for my
production websites but useful
to kinda learn the ins and
outs of creating a TagHelper.
>> Sure, maybe I'll need to
generate just some text to fill
a page so I can measure things.
>> Yeah, and you can imagine you
could create like a Lorem Ipsum
tag helper, or whatever, right?
>> Sure.
>> So I'm creating a class, and
I'm just putting it in the root.
But I'd recommend putting
in something like a tag
helpers folder or organize it.
>> It makes sense.
>> And tag helpers can also be
including in a NuGet package or
they can be in a separate
assembly, right?
We just saw that in the imports,
so you could create a Jeff's
favorite tag helpers assembly
and pull that in wherever.
>> Okay.
>> So I start by creating
a class and, Here's my class.
So I'm going to inherit
from tag helper, And
I'm gonna control that to
bring in the TagHelpers,
the namespace up there.
Yeah, the using statement.
So the first thing I'm gonna
wanna do is I want to repeat
something a certain
number of times.
So I'm gonna type creative
property and using the snippet
for properties,
which I very much like.
And so
I'm using an integer here.
Now the next thing is I need
to override one method that
it's not that hard and
you'll find it in the docs.
But I'll show you a little
trick that I use here,
which is, you can go in and
if I do Peak Definition,
which is a new feature
in Visual Studio.
I'm gonna scroll down here and
I'm gonna look there's
a ProcessAsync.
>> So what we're seeing
in that window is-
>> This is the code for,
this is the definition for
the actual TagHelper
that we're extending.
>> The abstract class
called TagHelper.
>> Exactly, exactly.
>> Okay.
>> So the TagHelper
abstract class has this
process async method.
>> Okay.
So I'm looking at
that declaration and
I'm going to use that as kind of
the start of what I'm gonna be
writing, right?
>> It makes sense.
>> So instead of virtual,
I'm gonna override.
And I want to make this async.
And the only thing that should
be complaining at this point is
that I'm not returning anything.
So, my step at this point is I'm
just going to use a for loop.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And,
because I'm repeating for
a certain number of times,
right.
So again, here I'm gonna say
from one to a Count, And
that's it.
So now I need to
actually write my code.
And it should just be one line
of code that I have to write.
So I'm gonna say-
>> And
this code will
generate the HTML?
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
>> So the way this process async
works is it gets called it's
an async method and
it just needs to output or
change my content.
So I'm gonna say output.,
if I can spell output,
dot, and then I'll say get.
Let me see, I'm forgetting,
actually, which one it is.
output.Content, that's it,
.AppendHtml, and
there's some other
things I can append.
In this case, I'm doing
AppendHtml, but I could do, for
instance, AppendFormat, and
I can use a formatting method,
right?
And so
now I need to say output., and
I will say GetChildContentAsync.
The reason I'm doing that is my
tag is gonna work sort of like
that environment tag
we looked at earlier.
So it's gonna say everything
inside of this tag, I need
to get that content, and so
this is how I'm accessing that.
And then one other thing is I
need to use an override here,
and I'm going to say
useCachedResult and
I'm gonna say false.. So-
>> That's an async method.
We need to await it, right?
>> You're right.
>> Fantastic.
>> And I think we're all happy.
Okay, so let's talk about
this code we just wrote.
So we wrote a Repeat Tag Helper.
So it's called RepeatTagHelper,
and
it inherits from
the TagHelper abstract base.
Because of that, this is a
RepeatTagHelper, I can go in and
just start using Repeat
as a tag helper.
We'll see that in a minute.
>> So,
repeat is my element name.
It's the tag I'm gonna
use inside my code.
>> Exactly, yeah.
>> Cool.
>> And if I wanted to change
attributes, there's actually
attributes that I would use in
here on my class [CROSSTALK].
So then I've declared
this count, and
this is magically
just gonna appear.
And the way it's gonna come in
is it's going to be an attribute
on my tag helper in my Razor,
okay?
So the same thing that we
had like, for instance,
in my register I had asp-for,
here I have Count, so
it's the same kinda thing.
And then when it actually fires,
this process, async, gets fired,
it's gonna be passed in both the
context, so we could read things
about what's going on outside,
as well as the output.
My output lets me
access the HTML, so
I am accessing what's
my child content.
And then I'm going to say append
that, and just repeating, right?
>> Sure.
>> All right, so now let's
go and put that to use.
I'm going to go into my
Index view page [LAUGH].
Old habits die hard.
So now I'm gonna go
into my index, and
I'm going to say repeat.
Now something's wrong here,
because that should be purple.
>> Yeah.
>> So I've forgotten one
important thing, and
you know what that is?
I need to go into ViewImports.
So that's-
>> That's right.
>> That's the thing,
we need to register that, and
that's a very important cue.
If you start using a tag helper
and you're not seeing that
IntelliSense, this is where
you need to turn that on.
So let me actually repeat.
And I'm also not seeing any
kinda IntelliSense in there.
So let's go into this,
and let's try this.
We'll do @addTagHelper *, and
here I need to use
a assembly name.
And so my assembly name
is WebApplication24.
Which, by the way,
have you registered that yet?
.com, .edu-
>> You know what?
I'm sorry,
I've been sliding here.
>> .biz.
>> I'm paying attention
to the module.
>> All right, so now,
did you see what happened there?
It just turned purple.
>> Nice.
>> And
we see when we mouse over it.
So now we know it's lit up.
>> And so now I can go in,
and also, if I hit space,
you see there, it's saying
I have a count property.
>> So let's repeat,
what's a good number?
>> Five.
>> Five's, I'm gonna go six,
cuz I'm just doing
one more today, okay.
And so we'll do here a p tag.
I will be repeated!!!
Okay, exciting.
So now, if we've done everything
right, we will see at the top of
our Index view,
we'll see I will be repeated!!!
And it will say six times.
Fingers crossed, but I'm feeling
pretty good about it because
that IntelliSense lit up.
>> It lit up, there we go.
>> There we go.
So we'll see this here,
I will be repeated!!!
And for extra fun, instead of
putting it around that tag,
let's actually repeat my
carousel, my entire carousel.
So I could do that by
collapsing this div, just to
show that it's not just a simple
p tag we're able to repeat.
This will work on anything,
right?
>> That's a lot of-
>> So I find this to be,
for a compelling,
we want WebApplication24
to become a huge brand.
And in order to do that, we
really need a lot of carousels.
So here you see that
that worked, right?
So that's, basically, we just,
we looked at in
the box tag helpers.
We wrote our own tag helper.
>> Yep.
>> It's helping or brand grow.
>> Absolutely,
lots of carousels.
>> And gain mindshare and
market share.
Yes, so now what I wanna do
is actually jump over and
look at some tag helpers other
people have written, because we
saw writing our own tag helper
is literally as simple as, here-
>> Implementing a method.
>> [LAUGH] Implementing
a method, exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> And the other cool thing is,
because of the way we pull
it into our application,
is just adding addTagHelper, and
then this is an assembly name.
Well, I can get assemblies off
a NuGet, I can get assemblies,
I mean, this is not
difficult to redistribute.
So I wanna show off just
a few of my favourites.
And one is from Damien Edwards,
and it is the TagHelperPack.
And this is something that he,
Damien Edwards is PM for
ASP.NET team.
And he actually built these tag
helpers as these were things he
kinda wished were in the box, or
thought, as he's building
applications he's like,
here's some things I
use in my websites.
>> Okay, possibly opinionated?
>> Yeah, exactly.
Some of these I would expect
to see actually ship in later
versions of ASP.NET Core.
So he's got example or
information here on
how to install it.
He's actually got it on MyGet,
which may move to NuGet,
eventually.
So I click through and this
is what I use to install it.
This is his actual website, and
it explains some of
the things he built.
So I wanna start by showing a,
here he's got field and
data annotation tag helpers.
And this is kind of
a neat thing here.
This starts to
show an example of how this
can become kind of useful.
So here, I've got
a customer class, and it is
getting these label names off
of these attributes, right?
So here it says,
my display name.
It could say First name, but
I'm gonna change this to say
Customer first name, right?
And then I'm gonna run this.
And so what's gonna happen is
this tag helper's job is it's
gonna actually pull those
labels off of these attributes.
So if I look down here,
we'll see there,
it says Customer first name,
okay?
So this is a way of
customizing a label,
how the label is generated.
And in this case, it's actually
pulling it off of the.
Display attribute.
>> Display attribute, exactly
and these display attributes
are handy for a lot of other
things like validation and
all that kind of stuff.
So he's got several others.
One other thing that
I really love and
I use in a lot of places
is his partial tag helper.
And this is something where
partials are a really
handy way of abstracting code.
So if I've got a bunch
of code in one view, and
I want to kind of move it to
another file, I can do that and
I can reference it as a partial.
So he makes it very easy to just
say, there's another syntax for
using it that's right.
You can say at partial and
I fill in some stuff and
it's just like, it's not pretty,
it's not [LAUGH] it's not
the code I wanna like.
>> It puts you into C# mode
instead of HTML coding mode.
>> Exactly and then one more
kind of more advanced one that
he's done is he's actually
got a mark down tag helper.
And so here you go and then you
can write things in mark down
and this mark down tag helper
complies it into HTML.
So all of these in
order to use these
he's got a handy sample
project available.
And if I go in and look at what
is the source code for these,
you'll see on my home
view he goes through and
actually makes use of all these.
So you know showing things
like how to set these up.
Yeah exactly, and you'll notice
again it's got that purple.
Lights up and
shows how those work.
So that's handy.
Another one I want to show
is a group of these from
David Paquette and David
Paquette has built these really
cool tag helpers to do
some other neat stuff.
So if we look at these,
he's got to take helpers for
things like bootstrap.
And so bootstrap is nice but
there's some things where I've
got to go and look up what
are these different attributes.
>> Yeah.
>> It's not auto completed and
it gets me out of my zone.
>> If I'm not a whiz with
bootstrap, if I'm not
using that on a daily basis,
I might not know all the CSS.
>> Exactly, yep, so
here he's got a website.
Both of these have
you can click off and
they've got example websites
that show how to set them up.
So here's an example of
something like an alert
tag helper.
So here, instead of going in and
writing div class
equals blah blah blah, and look
on the getbootstrap website,
l can just do alert and
then put the message name in.
And then when l click on that,
he's actually got,
here is the alert that
it shows there, and so
this shows the different kind
of alerts that are available.
Another one is a modal,
so modal one is not,
you know another one
actually progress bar.
Progress bars take a lot
of markup usually,
[LAUGH]
>> Yeah.
>> You have to nest all
this different stuff and
so here he's kind of
generating that for you.
One last one I want to
show was the modal.
So there it is,
here's the modal,
and here's one where you can
actually see something that's
in action, you can-
>> So
it's got a modal tag with
the body and the title?
>> Yep.
>> That's easy.
>> Yeah, so in other to do
that this is simplifying it.
And again I could go and
do this,
if I go to getbootstrap.com,
but the two things this kind
of gives me that are handy,
I'm gonna show the free
version of this.
The things that this gives
me is, one, it's a little
bit less markup and two,
I'll get that autocompleted.
So I can go through and
take advantage of that.
>> Absolutely,
I mean the intellisense that's
embedded there in Visual Studio
with that makes it so
easy to find these features and
get help when you need it.
>> Yeah, exactly.
So here's the markup.
You can just see here's the kind
of mark up I would have needed
for those progress bars versus
if we look at these progress
bars, it's a one liner.
>> Gosh yes.
>> So, and it's nice,
it's easy to buy into and
all that kind of stuff.
Now, what's cool with these is
if I want to learn how to
write my own tag helpers.
Or if I want to write a tag
helper similar to something
someone else has
already written.
>> Sure maybe I want to
extend their tag helper.
>> Exactly so I can go in and
look at either of these.
So for instance if I look
at David Paquette's and
we say well what is
he doing with for
instance this, like this
modal or the progress bar.
How is he generating that?
So if I look at the progress
bar tag helper.
I can see, here's what he's
doing how that's hooked up.
So something I mentioned but
didn't begin to earlier is
he's actually extending a div.
So here he's saying this is
called a ProgressBarTagHelper,
but it binds to a div,
it modifies a div.
And so here's how he does that
he says HtmlTargetElement so
this is going to light up for
any HtmlTargetElement that
uses these attributes.
And then the actual thing where
he, let me zoom back out.
The actual implementation
is that process async, and
it's actually not that much
code in order to do that.
>> And he's just writing up
that div that's sitting there.
>> Exactly.
>> So it's just that's how
he's writing this out.
And I only showed off his
bootstrap once, there are some
others that is got available
here is got for authorization
for generating test data
he's also got markdown one.
So that's handy and
then if we look at the ones that
Damian's done, for instance,
it's surprisingly a little
code most of the time.
[LAUGH] So if I look at that
partial and this is doing
something relatively I
would think complex,
it's including a partial.
If we look at
the actual code for
that, there's like almost
nothing here [LAUGH].
So, it's this process
async like we looked at
before and
this is all it's actually doing.
It's just modifying the output
to call in that partial.
>> It's calling the HTML
helper directly.
>> Yeah, so you know that's
an example of something
where l could write,
it's like yeah, it makes sense.
>> Absolutely.
>> It's like, he's just calling
directly into the thing.
So that's for the partial.
If we look at his mark down one,
and that's again,
you think well that's
got to be complex.
Well he's using another
markdown helper to do this and
then he is actually just
calling ProcessAsync.
So, he is using Markdig
here which is a popular
NuGet package that does
markdown processing, but
that's really all there
is to it on this.
So, kind of wrapping up.
What tag we looked at,
what tag helpers are.
>> Sure.
>> We showed when I do File,
New Project I've already got
some tag helpers that are in my
File, New Project application.
If I never wanna know anything
more about it than that,
they're making my life
easier because I can go and
write simpler and easier.
Razor, I can take advantage
of things like forms and
validation and all that and
pretty simple to wire things up.
If I wanna write my own, we saw
that thing where I went in and
I wrote my own and if we look at
what the code was involved for
repeat tag helper.
Like that's it,
it's like do process async and
I modify my output.
>> Yeah.
>> And then we look finally,
and we remembered and I'll just
call it out again because this
is something I forget and
you may forget yourself.
You've got to call this
addTagHelper in your view
imports.
>> Right.
>> You
could call it in one
individual view.
I can put it just at, I can just
import it for my index view or
whatever, or
I can do view import here and
import it everywhere.
>> That's a global import.
>> Global import, exactly.
>> Okay.
>> And then finally we looked at
how to make use of other
people's tag helpers.
And they've both made these
available and then for something
like this they'll show examples
of, here's how to use it.
You can install the package.
You call add tag helper and
then go to town.
>> And you're off and
running, cool.
>> And so the one final thing I
want to remind people of is that
there are some great
documentation about this on
docs.ASP.NET or excuse me,
docs.microsoft.com.
And it used to be on ASP.NET.
So this explains what they are,
tells you how to write your own.
Shows how to take
advantage of them.
>> It will keep you up
to date in the future as
the technology evolves.
>> Exactly.
>> Cool.
>> All right.
>> Well thanks a lot and
I hope you stick around for
our next module.