Hey Andrew, good to see you.
>> Hey Diego.
>> We are going to be talking
about Entity Framework Core
today, right?
>> That's right,
should we introduce ourselves?
>> Yeah, sure,
I am Diego Vega and
I work as the Program Manager
on the Entity Framework team.
I have been working on this for
a long time, so what about you?
>> Hi everyone,
my name is Andrew Peters and
I'm an Engineer on
the Entity Framework team.
>> Cool, so before we start,
I think that there are some
people that are going to be
watching this video that don't
know very much what
Entity Framework Core is about.
So I think we should give
a very short introduction,
explaining what it is and
what it is for.
>> Sure, sounds good.
>> Okay, why don't we just jump
to the code and create a simple
app, the minimal possible app
that you can write using EF.
>> Sure, so
Entity Framework Core is
what we call
an object-relational mapper.
So it's really a library that
helps you to basically get and
put data into a database.
It's all about querying data and
allowing you to modify that
data, and then saving
that to the database.
And what we really give you
is a programming model.
So would you like to kind of
talk a bit more about that?
>> I was trying to talk about
it while you show the code.
>> So, let's start down here,
I think.
>> Okay, so this is a model
what we call a set of classes
that represent a domain that
your application is allowed.
This case is a very
simple model,
it's actually oversimplified.
It talks about blogs,
because it's a model for
an application that
does blogging.
And blogs have a bunch
of properties in them.
They have an ID that is a unique
identifier for that blog.
And they also have a URL
as well because we know in
the Internet URLs are also
unique identifiers for things.
It becomes a way to
access the blog.
And in this case,
it doesn't even have a name
because it's super simplified.
But we have a theme because one
our demos is about how to change
the theme.
And a theme is also a very
simplified representation of
what the appearance
of the blog will be.
And in this case, it has
a name and it has a color for
the title, but it could have
many, many more properties.
>> Yeah, so this is showing one
of the high level features of
Entity Framework and that's the
ability to set up relationships
between your
different C# classes.
So we call these
navigation properties and
EF takes care of
managing these for you.
So if I create a blog and
set its theme, then you should
be able to save both of those
things to the database easily
and query them together
if you need to.
>> Yeah, it's also showing that
you can have very simple classes
that have properties on them and
have them work with
Entity Framework.
We are going to talk more about
what you can do with them,
but it's very important,
and it was not always
the case that these classes
don't need to know anything
about the Entity Framework Core.
>> Yeah and so
there's a special name for that,
what do we call that?
>> Yeah we call it POCO, or
persistent ignorant classes,
because they don't
need to know anything
about the persistence framework
that we are going to use.
POCO comes from Plain Old CLR
Object, which is an adaptation
from POJO, which was
the Java version of that.
But that is a history,
basically.
Now everybody assumes
that you can do this.
>> Yeah, and what it
really means here is that
these classes,
you can't really tell that any
framework core can use them.
So you don't have to
do anything special.
There are special things you
can do to kind of unlock
more advanced scenarios,
but right off the bat
you can just write the classes
in a very idiomatic way.
>> Yeah, why don't we
switch to the view context?
>> Okay so yeah,
the next sort of entry point
here is in the Entity Framework,
we have a very high level
object called the DbContext.
And this is the entry
point that you create for
the data access in your program.
>> Yeah, the simplest parameter
that you can write to UCF is
going to have a type that
derives from the DbContext
class that is defined
in Entity Framework.
And it's going to have a bunch
of properties of this type DbSet
that's generic on the classes
that you want to persist.
So if you set up a class like
this then you also need to write
a couple of methods.
I mean, you don't always need
to write both, but you need to
write at least the override for
OnConfiguring, which is
going to tell us about how to
connect to the database, mainly.
It can also be used to set up
a bunch of configuration for
different details and
settings that EF has.
And in the particular case of
an ASP.NET Core application,
the code that you would
normally put there, actually,
we usually put it in the
dependency injection container.
We can talk about
that more later.
>> Yeah,
I think we can show that later.
So, the key point here is
that the programming model
is inheritance based, so
it typically you inherit
off our type DbContext.
And this allows you to create
a strongly typed DbContext for
your specific application needs.
And in this case it's
the blogging context,
because it's for the blogging
software that we want to write.
And blogs and themes,
as Diego said,
allow us to get at the data.
And then two template
methods that you can override
OnConfiguring, for configuring
how you connect, for example.
And OnModelCreating for
configuring how you would
like to map the blog and
theme objects to the specific
tables in the relation database.
>> Yeah,
I was saying before that,
you don't always need
to write both methods.
The idea is that as soon as you
specify these two properties of
type DbSet, of your class,
EF is going to,
at runtime when it starts,
use reflection to look at
the properties of those types.
And infer what needs
to be persisted and
what types to use on the
database, depending especially
on the database that
you tell EF to use.
So in this case,
we had OnConfiguring.
I don't know if you
can show it there,
we have a code to a method
that's called UseSqlServer and
it passes the connection string.
So we know that we need to use
SqlServer and based on the types
of the properties on blog and
themes, we're going to figure
out what types of columns
we should create.
And by convention, we can
figure out a lot of things,
we can figure out that those
properties, and we can figure
out that they set a relationship
between theme and blog,
because you have a property
of type theme on the blog.
But there are some
details that we cannot
figure out automatically.
And then we have an API that
you can use to tell us.
And every time you need
to tell us those details,
that is when you have to put
code inside a more grading.
>> Yeah, so why don't we show
how this works more concretely.
So right now,
we don't have a database.
What we can also do is use
another piece of our stack that
we call migrations.
Migrations provide
a code-based way of building
a database schema and
evolving it.
One way we can
create a migration.
Is in the package
manager console.
I'm just gonna quickly set
this as my start up project.
There.
Now what I'm doing here is I'm
generating some code that's
going to land in our project.
And this is what we call
a migration file and
we can show you
what it looks like.
Okay, so
over here we can see that it
generated these two files.
And it opened up the one
we are interested in.
One of them we can consider
a Code Behind file, so
it's one that we managed
that you never usually edit.
But this is the one
that you can't edit.
We've scaffolded it by default,
and
what we've scaffolded
are these fluent API calls.
So we have a bunch of APIs that
correspond to typical database
DDL operations.
>> Yeah, DDL being the ability
to define tables and
objects on the data.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> So these two calls here
represent the creation of
the tables for the database.
It's the initial migration,
so it's the migration that
you would use in order to create
a database with all the schema
that you need in order to
persist these classes.
We can execute it, I guess.
>> Yeah, so
we started from a blank slate.
We didn't even have a database,
so we called this one initial,
and this is kind
of our first one.
So we've got some
create tables here,
we're gonna create
the themes table, so
ef has, by convention, decided
to call the table themes.
It's scaffolded a bunch
of columns, and
it's figured out what
their type should be.
You can see here we're doing
a value generation strategy as
well, so what this is is, in SQL
Server, our convention is that
you want an identity
column if your primary key
is non composite, and
of an integral type like int.
>> Okay,
>> So we have this second
command here, update database.
Okay, that's telling us that
there's already an object named
themes in the database.
So it could be that
the database is already there.
>> Yep.
>> So
let's just quickly drop that.
Wait for this to load.
No, thank you.
So I think it's this one.
Let's try that again.
So we've run these demos a few
times, and we need to make sure
to clean out the database
back to a clean slate.
>> Okay.
>> So there we go,
we applied the migration.
So what that did was ef
consumed all of these calls and
executed them, and basically
part that was to generate
the SQL corresponding to them,
and
apply it to the target database
from the connection string.
Should see it in here now.
There's the two tables, and
what's this one, Diego?
>> That one keeps track of all
the migrations that have already
been applied to this database.
So that we can also reason
about that when you say,
okay update database, we know
exactly what migration you have
already in the database and
which ones need to be applied.
>> Yeah, so we kind of implement
a versioning strategy there.
So we can see the idea of
the migration here corresponds
to this name here.
>> You will also see that at the
bottom of the screen now we have
some create index methods.
That means that we inferred that
we needed to create an index for
the relationship that makes
operations like delete faster on
those tables.
What else can we show for this?
>> I think we can show this,
too.
This is pretty cool.
So this is a new
feature that's coming.
And this is the ability
to also have data
put into the database
when you migrate it.
So we'll call this seed data,
and here we're setting up
a bunch of things by default.
>> So if you are familiar
with you would remember that
we had migrations also, and
we had a seeding capability.
You can say, okay, whenever
we create this database, or
apply variations,
we're going to prepopulate some
details around the database with
data that then you can use
as reference data mostly.
We decided to implement
something different.
To have a different design on
EF Core that we believe is
much better and can give
you much more flexibility.
So this is basically, the seed
data is part of the model.
And whenever we are calculating
the difference between
two models,
seed data also becomes part
of that computation
of the differences.
So whenever you add data or
you remove data from the model,
we figure out what we need to
do in the migrations as well.
>> Yeah, so we can show that.
It also works with
changing the data.
So here we're gonna change theme
1 to actually use AliceBlue
as the color.
And this will also
kind of give an example
of the migration's workflow.
So now we've made this change,
we wanna share it with
other developers on our team,
potentially.
And so what we do is we can
create another migration.
Build.
So each time you make a change
that will change the database
schema or seed data, you can
generate a new migration that
will now be shared
amongst your team.
And they can just run that, and
their local databases will
be brought up to date.
You can also use it to deploy
to production via script, or
using code.
>> I think we need to
add migration
>> Yes, generate.
Okay, so
here you can see it looks a lot
different than the last one.
That's because we deduced
that the only thing that's
changed since we applied
the last one was this change to
the seed data.
>> Yeah, you see also there's
an up and a down method.
The up method will make
this migration the current,
if we execute that, we
are going to make the database
be of this current version.
>> Bring it up to date, yep.
>> Yeah, if you tell us that
you want to reword that,
then we're going to execute the
down method that is going to set
the color back to
what it was before.
So we need to record
that in the migration.
>> So down is really about
rolling back to previous states,
which might happen if you deploy
to production, for example, and
something goes wrong.
Down provides a way to back out
the change that was made by up.
>> Yeah, can we show the script
that we generate the SQL?
>> Sure, for this migration?
>> I think so, yeah.
>> Script migration.
>> Yeah.
>> So this is nice because you
can just generate a script,
a SQL script, and hand it off
to someone if you don't have
direct access to run against
the production database,
which is pretty normal.
>> Yeah, this gives you,
actually,
the way we execute this command
gives you the whole script for
creating the database
from scratch.
>> Yup.
>> But it's going to
include the values for
the data that we have, the seed
data that we have there.
>> Exactly, and
we should see it.
Yeah, you can see
the color change from red.
This is the first migration,
and then down at the end,
we should have
the second migration.
So here.
>> Yeah.
>> So you can see it's really
sequential, it's not that we
just deduced that the color
should start at AliceBlue.
>> Yeah, there is also another
interesting detail there,
in this script, that we
are setting identity insert,
on the themes table, OFF and ON.
That's something that
we do automatically,
because in SQL Server,
if you know about that,
identity columns normally
cannot be updated.
In this version of seeding
we have the ability to do it
because you are asking for
a specific ID value.
We are going to do whatever it
takes to make it of that value.
>> Yeah.
>> And in this case,
we need to go around it and
apply the workaround for
SQL Server.
The previous version of EF
didn't have the capability, so
it could not do it.
>> I wonder it might be better
to not introduce identity
columns for seed data.
>> That could be
an option there.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
Let's, we might as
well apply that one,
I guess,
>> Yeah.
>> Bring us up to date.
Okay, now,
what else have we got here?
Okay, so this is just
a little program that we'll
leverage on you blog in context.
And all it does is look for the
themes, and print them out, so
we should just run that
to see where we're at.
Okay great, so we can see that
was blue, it's been updated, and
we can see basically that
querying the database was super
easy.
We were able to
write a normal for
each loop over that DbSet
property that we created.
Underneath, Has done a lot of
work, it's generating a query to
the database, it's figured out
how to create the theme objects
efficiently, performs
really fast.
And the end result is,
that you'd just get back
a stream of themes.
>> Okay, I think we
should try also to do one
hour demo that shows some of
the basic operations that we do,
besides the features.
>> Okay, sounds good.
>> Which one do you
think we can do?
>> Flexible mapping
might be a good one.
We can talk about some different
styles of creating a pokas.
>> Yeah, sounds good.
>> So I'm just gonna reset.
All right, should we start
with the entity types?
Or entity type?
>> Yeah, this model has only
one class, that is a blog.
And it's a little bit more
complete than the other one,
because the purpose of this,
they must be defined.
We have more properties
like the name,
and things that you
will expect to see.
But we decided to do something
special for the URL, right?
>> Yeah, so I think we were
interested in using a field
mapping for the URL.
So what that means is,
by default,
you would often write your
classes with properties.
But you don't have to, you can
also map directly to fields.
And this provides kind of a more
encapsulated way of structuring
data inside your Poka.
>> Yeah, also there is
a continuum of features
that we call flexible
object mapping.
We have only gotten
started with these.
In the beginning we
started with a Support
simple classes or pokas.
Then we started supporting
simple objects with properties.
Now, we support field mapping.
And there are certain features
that we're going to be working
on, that make it even more
flexible, and can allow you
to have more freedom or
how you design your domain more.
If you want to use, dictionaries
maybe some day will support that
also for your properties,
if you want to use a constructor
that takes some of this property
values in, will recognize it.
That's not something that we
do in the conversion, but
something we're going
to be working on.
>> So, our goal is
really to allow you to
define your classes, the way
they way that you would like to.
And then, allow you to configure
EF to be able to map them
to the database
structure that you want.
And those things
can kind of evolve,
and be shaped separately.
>> Okay.
So in this case I see that
you added a private string
on this call URL property.
>> Yeah, so I created the field.
I made the property read only,
and
then we have this method that
we call when we wanna set it.
And this is useful, maybe we
want to perform some custom
validation here,
so domain logic.
This allows us to kind of
create more of an encapsulated
implementation of what
it means to sit the URL.
>> Okay, but from the
perspective of persistence you
may want your persistence
library to just access the field
to set the value there,
that it's read from
the column and the data.
>> Yeah for sure.
So I think we need a bit
of configuration, right?
>> Mm-hm.
>> So here we've got
a bit more fluent API.
It's hopefully pretty readable,
what we're saying is for
the entity blog,
it has a property of type string
called URL, and
is backed by this field.
>> Yeah, when we specify that
name URl with uppercase,
we usually talk about those
as basically the conceptual
property, that is a property
conceptually on this class,
although the dotNet
class doesn't have
the property setter.
We still reason about the fact
that there is a property there.
>> Yeah, so this is kind of, I
guess would say hybrid mapping,
because the property
is there for reading.
We have the actual underlying
storage in the class is this
underscore URL field.
>> We also recognize some
different common conventions for
naming fields automatically.
So in this case,
actually the HasField
is only there to tell
us to use the field.
>> Yeah.
>> I guess but even, that kind
of underscore url, with lower
cases, has something that we
will recognize by convention.
>> Yeah, for sure so I got us
illustration of that would be,
I guess if we did
something like this.
>> Yeah.
>> So
we're kind of varying
the names to no longer match,
what EF you think they
should be called?
>> Yeah.
>> But
you could still set
it up that way.
>> There are some other
variation that we support,
which is to not have
the field at all.
I mean in this case, we all
ready have like a property
at all, that depends
on the field in there,
but there is another variation
which is call entity of
blog has a property of
type string with name URL.
And there's nothing in
the class at all that
is holding that value.
>> Yeah.
>> But that's something that we
call shadow properties,
and when you have those,
what happens is that EF, on the
change structure, that reduces
to tracking modifications
that you make on the data.
It will keep track
of that value,
keep it on the instance
of the of the entity.
So basically, we keep additional
properties like extension
properties for you.
>> Yeah exactly.
So yes, there you'll see
the shadow properties,
where we keep the data totally
outside of the instance.
So here, there is no place for
the URL to be stored on this.
When we retrieve a blog,
we will give you the blog, and
we will also keep track
internally of the value
of URL for
each blog that we gave you.
So it kind of makes your object
dependent on the DB context.
There's another mode you can
run, which is no tracking.
Where we will keep track of
the values in a different way
during the query.
But in that way, we will
allow you to still query for
different URLs, for example.
>> Would you like to show
how to use this model or
something else?
>> Yeah, I think we can quickly,
I'll run it.
It's not, I can probably
just back it all out.
>> Okay.
>> So
let's have a look at our main.
We just do some database set up.
So here, we should probably
quickly discuss this.
So we showed migrations.
These sort of a red way like
a red application development
style, where for example
if you're running test, so
you're running prototype at.
So you wanna get something
off and running quickly.
We have these database APIs,
which we'll just delete the
whole database and recreate it.
>> Yeah, it's not recommended
for production or for
anything super serious and
complicated but
it's the right way for
testing and proof reading.
>> Yeah.
To show.
So a lot of this pattern where
we just recreate the database.
And so we're creating up
BloggingContext again,
creating a blog, setting its
URL, adding it to the database.
So, I guess we're showing a few
APIs we haven't seen yet.
So we saw querying of a DBC,
but the DBC,
you can also add new items
into and remove items from.
So it's kind of
a programming model,
a collection like programming
model for your data.
So what you typically do is,
you have a bunch of these calls,
manipulating which objects you
want to save in which way.
And then, save changes
at the end is going to
figure out what all those
changes were and apply them.
So, we've got login on as well,
it's another thing
worth mentioning.
Entity Framework Core
has rich blogging.
And this really
helps you understand
the kind of interactions that
EF is having with your backend.
So here, you can see, for
example, in short, created.
So we're creating
a database here.
This is our save changes insert.
As per usual blogs has
an identity column, so
we need to select
back the value.
And then, at the end our query.
So this is the query over
the blogs and then, the value.
So you can see if Core really
helps here because this kind of
automates a bunch of stuff that
you would normally need to do.
For example, if you're
using identity columns, and
also just the unit
of word pattern.
I've made a bunch of changes
on the client and memory.
And I want to understand
those changes and apply them.
>> Yep, so in this case,
in this simple demo,
we only had this one operation
before the SaveChanges, but
you can have multiple operations
there or multiple entities.
And when there are relationships
between them, we will figure out
the right order to apply those
modifications in the database.
So that, for instance,
child entity is always get
inserted after the parents so
that the primary key already
exists in the database.
And whenever we need
to delete something,
we'll do it in
the previous order.
>> That's right.
>> Okay, so, you think we should
switch to another demo, or
is there anything interesting
on this one that we can show?
>> We probably need to add
posts for it to be a blog.
>> Okay.
>> So we could do that.
So, We're kind of
evolving schema here,
so we're gonna create a post.
This one we'll have a,
Second Id.
Maybe a string Title,
and maybe the Body.
What are we missing?
So, we wanna link it to blog,
right?
This kinda comes back to what
programming model we want
now in our app.
So if you suggests in our
application, we get the blog,
and we want to always access
the posts of the blog,
we can do that, right?
>> Yep, probably,
we can have a public list or-
>> Something like that.
Collection of blog,
of posts, sorry.
Posts.
Okay so,
let's imports ICollection.
Now, do we need to
do anything else?
>> I think in this case, we
don't need to do anything else,
but we could decide that we
also want to have a link from
the post going back to the blog.
>> Okay.
>> Would you like to do that or
we can skip it?
What is your style?
How do you decide that?
>> Are you thinking
a reference to the blog, or
are you thinking something
like the foreign key?
>> It could be both, or
it could be either of those.
>> Okay.
>> They are all possible, and
whenever you don't create
a property, EF Core is going to
still be able to maintain
the relationship.
But if you want to have
the value of the foreign key
in the property because you want
to render it in database or
something, then you can do it.
>> Sure, so, just like Diego
said, if we don't define
the foreign key here, if it's
gonna introduce something.
And it's gonna introduce
a shadow property just like we
saw before.
So we can probably observe that.
Okay so, our database
looks a little different.
We're now creating
the post table.
And here,
you can see the BlogId.
So currently, it's not defined
on the post entity, but
EF created it anyway, and
EF will manage its value.
So this is nice if you want your
entity types to be really poker.
>> Yeah.
>> And
not have any sort of
database artifacts in them.
>> Yep.
>> But we could also
have edited down here.
So, Oops.
And we need to probably call
it something different to
make interesting, I guess.
Blog, oops, BlogFK.
>> So now,
what do we expect to happen?
>> I would expect EF to,
do you want me to lie or
do you want me to
tell the truth?
>> Tell the truth.
>> Okay, EF is not going to be
able to figure out that that's
a foreign key.
That is supposed to point to the
primary key on the other side.
So that's going to consider
that that's a normal property
because we are not following
the right naming convention.
>> Yeah, I think that's right.
So EF has a lot of
conventions built in that try
to identify common patterns, in
order to sort of pair things up.
So if we see a property
here that's called BlogId
that matches one of
our conventions.
So that convention is,
we found a property on the child
that has the same name as
the primary key on the parent.
So that's kind of a natural
way for us to match things up.
But if you call this BlogFK
that doesn't match one of our
existing conventions.
So what we will expect is
probably another shadow FK.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah, and so
here, you can see
we've got there.
>> Yep, the property that you
asked for got created, but
it's not considered
a foreign key.
And you have still created
a shadow foreign key, and
made the foreign key constraint.
>> Okay, well, let's fix that.
>> And there are several
way to fix it, actually.
>> Yeah, Fluent.
So one way is Fluent API.
We want to, sorry,
we want to configure
blog because we're
going to configure the,
HasMany.
So this is our way of
targeting the posts'
collection on the blog.
So this takes a lambda.
So now, we've sort of addressed
the posts' navigation.
And because we need to do
that to tell EF what we wanna
configure.
>> Okay.
>> We call WithOne.
This just allows us to get at
the foreign key configuration
and sort of explicitly calls out
that there's no back reference
from the post to the blog.
That's ForeignKey.
Now we can do the strongly type,
because we have the property, so
it should be available
in IntelliSense.
So this fluent API is geared
around IntelliSense as well,
in terms of just being able
to dot into things and
reference things that way.
Look good?
>> Yeah, it looks good.
>> There we go.
So the shadow property is gone
and we've configured EF to
explicitly use the property that
we want to be the foreign key.
>> Yeah, you can see
the cost paying also.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
So where else can we show?
Would you like to talk
about performance or?
>> We could show a few
other things first, maybe.
So we could talk
about functions or-
>> I think that sounds good.
>> Okay.
So this is a new feature
that's in EF Core 2.0.
Do you want to talk about
what it's roughly about?
>> Yes, so we have had some
feedback for a long time
from people that wanted us to
improve one of our features.
So the feature is
called ego loading, but
we usually refer to it as
the include method, cuz that's
how you specify that you want
loading in your inquiries?
>> So what does this mean to do?
>> So that method is telling
us that whenever you query for
a blog in this query, we should
also cover the relationship
that it has to post.
There is a navigation
property and
bring the instances of the post
as well as part of the results.
>> Okay, that makes sense.
So when I'm enumerating
all the blogs I got back,
this will be populated
with all the posts.
>> Yeah, exactly.
So what people have been
telling us for a while is that
they don't necessarily want
all the posts to include,
that they want to apply
a filter on that include.
For instance, let's say that
the user has been blogging for
many years and
it has too many posts and
I just want to log
the ones from last year.
>> I see, okay.
>> So that's the feature that
we have been talking about.
And we look at it and
we decided that we didn't want
to design it exactly like that.
But we wanted to have something
that is more declarative and
the ability to say
at the moral level.
Okay, whenever you're ready for
pause, apply this filter,
and of course you are going to
have ways to turn that off, but
general by default,
just apply this filter.
So we came up with
a solution for that.
And that's, we call it
sometimes lower query filter,
sometimes more level query
filters, sometimes just filters.
>> Yeah, so, just to make it
even more concrete, the way you
filter and link is obviously
what this Where method.
So this allows you to
define a predicate
that will be used to either
include or exclude results.
And so what this feature allows
is essentially to be able to
define that in on model creating
in such a way that it will
always apply it to queries
of the target type.
This example we essentially set
up two filters, because we're
trying to implement two
cross cutting behaviors.
We want to implement
soft delete.
So the ability to mark a row
in the database is deleted
without actually
deleting it physically.
And then multi-tendency,
so the ability associate
a row in the database with
the tenant id, such that
we can later on only pull back
the data for a given tenant.
So.
Start with the first one.
Here you can see that API, so
it's a non model creating,
it's again,
we address the entity.
So it's the post.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And IsDeleted is
actually just a property
A first class property
on the entity itself.
So we're not using a shadow
property or anything,
we just created the property
maybe we need this in the UI and
maybe it's just the style
that we wanna use.
So we were able to easily,
essentially write a small link
predicate fragment here and
associate that with
the metadata in our model.
>> Yep, so the fact that it's
a property makes it possible,
and because we add some code
that we're going to show and
search in this.
Now you have two ways to
mark an entity as deleted,
you can either set
the property to true, or
you can call the APIs
to remove the entity.
We have some code that we put
in SaveChanges this that is going
to basically translate that
removal into a modification.
So that's a code.
Especially whenever you save
changes before you actually
save changes to the
database we are going to look
for all the change tracking
entries that we had for
post that are mark affiliated.
And we are going to switch
that back to modified and
put the property and
the right state so
that marks are deleted,
as deleted.
>> Yes, so
this is a good example of
the more advanced extension
point that you can use,
which is just to override
sort of changes.
The way this works is that,
internally inside the DB context
we have these things
called entries.
An entry is really a data
structure that wraps around one
of the objects that we've given
you, and it's kind of in charge
of keeping track of its original
data, any new data that's
any of the changes that have
been made, that kind of thing.
So instead of changes, you can
manipulate these entries before
we actually read them to make
the final set of changes call.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's
what we're doing here.
Find all of the ones
that say they deleted and
turn them into modified.
>> Yep.
>> Whilst also setting
the new value for
this deleted property.
>> Mm-hm.
>> So that's pretty useful.
>> So you want to show
the multi tenancy part?
Would you like to
just execute a query?
>> Sure, why don't we first,
what I'm gonna do is
Think it's useful to
disable that filter.
Did I said startup project?
>> Yep.
So this is our kind
of initial state,
where we haven't got any
filters defined yet.
And we can see that we're
querying all of the blogs and
the posts, and we're getting
Tenants for everyone, and
we are getting all of
the deleted and the not deleted.
>> Yup.
>> So, that's sort of.
Right now, the query is naive.
We will enable to
soft delete filter.
Run it again.
Okay, so good.
We are only getting
IsDeleted: False.
So we very easily implemented
it's like a crosscutting
pediment we wanted to implement
inside our application.
>> Yeah.
>> And this this is
affecting entities that
we bring to the results
as part of an include and
not as part of the main entity
that we're creating for.
>> Exactly so if you remember,
The way we were enumerating
these things was that we were
bringing the posts together with
the blogs and then we were just
doing this nested loop off
the navigation properties.
So here you can see in the query
when we select out of the posts
we just select on the filter.
That's quite nice.
>> Yep.
>> Now this filter will also
apply if I query
post the top level.
It would apply any time that I,
any query that we generate for
posts.
>> Yep.
>> That's it.
If, how do you the opt-out.
>> Yeah,
you've got to turn it off.
Should we show that?
Quickly, and
then we can go on.
Okay, so let's say your
application has an admin screen
and an administrator can go
in and undelete these things.
This is how you would
implement that.
IgnoreQueryFilters just turns
off all the filters for
the query.
So we get them back again.
It's kind of like the opt out.
>> Okay.
>> Okay multi-tendency?
>> Sounds good.
>> Little different,
do you wanna explain why
we have this difference?
>> Yeah.
So this is a little bit more
sophisticated I guess than
a data filter, because first
of all we have a tenant
ID field on the DE context class
that we need to reference.
So we need to match the tenant
ID of that particular instance
of the context with
the entities on the database.
And we are keeping track of the
fact that when the query filter
was defined,
Do index execution of
the creating method
on the first context.
This was maybe some tenantId
that was our target site on that
first instance.
>> Yep.
>> We have this optimization
that we're not executing them or
creating method every
time you use the context.
We only execute it once.
We create them all and
we cache it.
But we want to always
use the current value
of this _TenantId field.
The other part of next is little
bit more complicated is this
access to
the EF.Property method.
There is a way that you can
access properties on an inquiry
using the F core that works for
every property.
It works basically for
properties that are first class,
properties on the class,
it works for shallow properties,
and it also works for properties
that are mapped to the fields.
And it's an also
interesting point
because you an see that it
starts with the EF class.
You want to talk a bit
about what we did there?
>> Sure.
Yes, so we had a need for
essentially like a static entry
point API that we could just,
you could reference from
anywhere very easily.
So we kind of with those EF
class and it all goes to be
static and very easy to find and
very easy to type.
And so we have a few of
these static APIs and
they will all hang
off this EF class.
Another one is I
guess compile query.
So these static methods that
allow you to get more advanced
query performance by taking
over the caching of queries for
example.
And then we have this functions
property which allows you to,
similar to EF property but
within a link query explicitly
specify database function
using CLI method.
>> Yeah, having this static
entry point viewers have
very good discoverability on the
APIs, so basically you can learn
EF by exploring what is
hanging from this class.
And was of course from
the DE context class.
So those are the two primary
entity points that
you have to use.
Anything that is not related to
the current DE context instance
that you are using, is going to
primarily be hanging from EF.
>> Yeah, and so as Diego said
In the blog we don't have
a tenantId property, so it's
similar to our first example we
were talking about, where we're
just using a field mapping.
So we reference it this way.
>> Yeah, we did something
also this for this, right?
>> Yeah we also did
the same kind of thing, so
just to step back,
The reason tenantId comes into
the constructor here because
consider a web application.
Every request is getting a new
blogging context instance.
And so as part of that,
as part of the request itself
we're gonna have some app logic,
figure out what the tenant
should be for that request.
And then we're gonna create
the context with that tenant, so
essentially scoping this
context to a given tenant.
So we know that this instance
is for a given tenant.
We've set up the filter and
then we've saved changes.
We can, from saved changes we
can actually sit the tenant
because we have
the right value here.
>> Yep.
>> So any entities that
were added make sure that
the tenantID is seated
to the current tenant.
>> Okay, you want to try it?
>> Okay, so
we got the Diegos only,
I think that's what we wanted.
Let's just check.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Yep, there we go.
I think we can change it.
So a key point here is kind
of what Diego was alluding to
before, or
model creating rounds once,
we detected that underscore
TenantID should in fact be
a parameter in the query.
And so you can see here
it's parameterized.
So the query is compiled once,
each time it runs,
get the context instance
that's running it,
pull out the tenant ID from that
and plop it into the query.
>> I wanted to show some links,
resources.
So this is basically some links
that you can use to learn
more about Entity Framework Core
and how to use it.
We have all the demos that
we have been showing today,
those are in a repository on
GitHub under Andrew's account.
This anpete efdemos and
then we have all of our source
code and our issue tracking.
So the backtracking we do
it all on GitHub as well.
It's in this http.net
core repository,
and we have
documentation also on
the Microsoft docs
website under EF core.
There's also,
we are very soon going to
have the Entity Framework 6
documentation alongside
this one under EF 6.
These are our Twitter accounts,
we have an official account for
EF that is called
@efmagicunicorns, that
if you run into anything that
you cannot find an answer for
a question for stack overflow.
Or you cannot find a way to
tell something you are seeing
is a bug or something, you can
priority ping us there and
we'll respond.
And for personal ones, and
then we have this blog that is
the .NET blog that we use every
time we have an announcement.
So anything else that
we should talk about?
>> No, just encourage folks that
are interested to check out
our GitHub project, and even
potentially try and contribute.
So we have a bunch of people
that have already made
contributions, and we're super
excited when we get pull
requests from the community, no
matter how small or how large.
>> Yeah, also the the ASP.NET
documentation contains some
interesting tutorials that
includes using the EF Core and
in documentation for EF Core
you're going to find some some
explanations of
specific features.
I recommend that you when
you're trying to learn how to
use EF Core in
the context of ASP.NET
core those are really
good resources.
>> So thank you.