Hey there, welcome back to this
module about ASP.NET Core.
My name is Jeff Fritz.
>> I'm Jon Galloway.
>> And, Jon, we built an
application in that last video
where we showed how to log
in to our application, but
I've already got
a Microsoft account and
a Twitter account and
a Facebook account.
Can I use one of those to
login to my application?
>> Well, yeah,
that's exactly what will show.
Password are terrible.
>> They are.
>> If you remember
on the last thing,
I can't miss type my password.
>> Mm-hm.
>> I wanna
manage as few
passwords as possible.
And as an application
developer I wanna manage this
few passwords as
well as possible.
I don't want people breaking
into my application and
stealing user passwords, people
sometimes reuse passwords on
other sites,
I don't wanna deal with that.
So what's a lot better is if
I can let people login to my
application using Google,
Microsoft, Facebook,
Twitter, etc.
And let them deal with it.
>> Sure.
>> So we'll show how to do that.
I'm on my application.
>> Okay.
>> And I'm gonna click on
Log In.
And when I do that, you'll see
over on the left side it has
this kind of standard user
account with email and password.
Over on the right side though
it says, there's no external
authentication services
configured.
See this article for details.
>> So more boiler plate text
there that instruct us how to
configure that application
if we wanna add the feature.
>> Exactly,
this is prompting me.
This is saying all you've
got set up right now is user
name and password.
There are some steps to
configure it in your application
so that it can use external
authentication services, but
here's how to do it.
Now you need to go through
these different steps for
each provider.
So, for Facebook, for Twitter,
for Google, for Microsoft, for
other open idea or
out to providers.
So you need to go through and
configure that.
It's not a whole
lot of steps but.
So we're gonna go
through in this one.
I'm gonna use some
Microsoft account.
But you could use whatever, and
the steps are all kinda
written here in the dots.
And it was off that link I
clicked in my application there.
So what I'm gonna do here is I'm
going to start with creating
an application using
Microsoft application, right?
So I'm going to go in and
I've gone to apps.dev.microsoft.com
>> Okay.
And I'm gonna click
on Add an app.
So now I need to give
it My MVA Sample.
And then I could go through
here, there's this guided setup
and if I do that, it's actually
going to give me like a little
wizard to point me at
some sample code stuff.
But I'm an expert here, I've
done this a gazillion times I'm
just gonna click on Create, and
so it's going to go out and
provision a new application for
me.
So now let's make sure that we
are kind of following along
here and I'm going to go in and
find where it's got
my Microsoft instructions.
So, this is kind of showing
how to configure it
on the Microsoft side, right?
So, you will log in,
you will create and
there you will see there is my
application I've just added.
>> Okay.
>> All right, so now let's
kinda work through this.
So, in here, that's my name.
I will,
as I work down the list, I will
need to generate a new password.
So when I click this
generate password, this is,
it's a secret.
I'm going to use this in my
application, and I need to store
this, so when this pops up it's
only gonna show it to me once.
So I just copied that.
And I'm gonna go over
into notepad here and
I'm going to paste
that down here.
So this is from a previous one,
I'm just going to,
that's my password there.
And then here is
my Application Id.
So those are the two things I'm
going to need to configure in my
app in order to do that.
So I'm actually going to be
pasting these as secrets
into my application.
So just while I'm here I'm gonna
go ahead and paste this in here.
And this here.
This is going to be
information I'm going to be
using in my application
in just a minute.
>> So, these two data points.
This is effectively
the user ID and password
that your application will
use to access the Microsoft
account website and do a check
on user ID's and passwords.
>> That's exactly.
>> Okay.
>> So my application needs a way
to call into a Microsoft
account to the Microsoft, or
whatever it is Twitter,
Google, etc, etc.
I'm this registered application
I need you to look up
the user for me.
>> Okay.
>> So
that's how we're doing that.
So then here I'm gonna click in,
I'm gonna say Add Platform and
at this point I'm going
to need a URL for this.
And this part is
actually is important.
You've got to get,
I mean it's all important.
But this part is,
if you get this wrong,
it's just not gonna work and
you'll be frustrated, right.
Unlike some other errors
that you can get developing,
if you get this part wrong,
it just doesn't work.
>> Man.
>> You don't get
an error message.
You just get a couldn't find
your application kind of thing.
So what I need to do is I'm
going to look at my app and
I have this URL.
It's local host,
blah, blah, blah.
So I'm going to copy
that part in here.
And then I need to get
the second part which is
sign in dash Microsoft.
So within my application
there's actually,
there's kind of route generated
to enable this call back.
So I'm gonna go like that.
Right, so what this tells the
Microsoft account registration
thing is once you kinda look
this person up, here's how you
call back into my application
and say they're good to go.
>> Okay.
>> Right.
>> And
it'll notify your application.
That it's John Galloway signed
in with his Microsoft account.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
>> Will pass that information
over who that person is.
So an important thing here
is once you type that in,
you gotta hit the save button.
>> Okay.
>> So I got that wrong before I
went through and I was like,
what's going on?
Why isn't that working?
So that is an important step.
[LAUGH] So now that we have
that information configured
over on the Microsoft side,
on the Microsoft account side.
Now, I need to take that
information, here's the password
and all that and I need to
configure this in my app.
So I actually wanna do this
using the secret management
thing that's built into,
built into ASP.NET Core.
>> Okay.
>> So remember,
I've got these things here,
this is my application ID and
password.
>> Right.
>> And
I might be tempted
to just go and
put this in my appconfig or
my appsettings json.
>> App Settings Json.
Don't do that.
>> That's a bad idea, right?
Because oops, I might check that
in the source control, etc. Absolutely.
>> I don't wanna do that.
So there's a thing built
into ASP.NET Core that has,
it's called user secrets.
And so I can just go in, oops,
I can grab this bit here.
And paste that in.
So this user secrets thing is
just a standard JSON file, and
what this is doing this will not
get checked into source control.
And what I'm gonna wanna do
then is when I deploy this
application to production, say
I'm using Azure I would go in
and set an application
setting for that.
>> Mm-hm.
>> I would set in a environment
variable in another server, etc.
I wanna store this on the server
as an environment variable and
not in source code
with my application.
>> Right.
>> Makes sense?
>> Keep production
configuration in production.
>> Exactly.
Okay, so now the one final
thing I need to do is,
I've got these secrets stored.
And I need to go in and
I need to tell it, hey,
use Microsoft account and
here's how to look at that
application ID and password.
So I'm going to go
into my start up and
right below the place where
it does the AddIdentity.
So he's right, it kind of
configure the basic identity.
I'm going to, on this line here,
I need to stop my app in order
to make source code changes.
So I'll go in here and
I'll paste that.
So this says AddAuthentication
turn on the Microsoft account
and for the Microsoft account
use this client ID and
this client secret.
So they use some
different names,
client ID, client secret
you'll notice in here that
the Microsoft account called it
something slightly different.
>> Yeah they call
them a password.
>> But there's basically
it's a user ID and
some sought of password
secret sought of thing.
>> Okay.
>> So now I've got that setup,
I'll verify in my steps
that I'm done here.
So here it calls that out by
difference in terminology.
And now I can just
run my application.
Now in my case,
I've already signed in with my
Microsoft account so hopefully
I'll just be able to kinda
click through and it will work.
All right so
it's starting on up.
So now I am going to log
out as test.test.com.
And then hit Log in.
And now you'll see this
button here and it's laid up.
So if I go through that help,
and I configure also, say,
Twitter and Google, etc.
Those will show up here, too.
>> Cool.
>> So
now I'm gonna click on this.
It calls over,
it redirects over.
Now I've got a few different
accounts with
Microsoft accounts.
Fortunately Microsoft has
kinda support for that, right.
So here it says okay we
need your permission.
The thing I wanna verify
here is the user is
that it's my Microsoft sample.
Which I'll say application
that I think it is.
Right and I'll say Yes.
And so now it's continuing that
it's go, it's logged in and
now it's redirected back
in to my application.
This would be the part where
if I had gotten that call back
URL wrong, this is where
it would have blown up.
>> You would have ended up
in never, never length.
>> It would have the Microsoft
authentication thing would have
said couldn't find this.
So it would show me in an error.
So now it says great,
we logged you in,
we looked up your email address
for that Microsoft account so
you can just click Register.
And now, this is me.
So if I click through on
this it shows here's my
external log in and that's my
registered external log in.
>> You can have more than one
registered external login for
a user which is kind of neat.
>> And then I could go in and
configure things like Two
factor authorization, etc.
>> And
still increase the security
of your account on
this application.
>> Exactly, so what we saw here
was kinda the basic steps of
going in and getting out of the
password management business.
I don't wanna manage
passwords in my application.
I want another bigger service
where people are, run around
with pagers and worry about
all that stuff all day long.
So, what I've done is
set up an external
authentication provider using
Microsoft and I've shown you
where you could also hook
up Google, Twitter etc.
>> Cool, all right.
Thanks so much for
sticking around and
seeing about how to configure
authentication here.
Hope you'd come back and
join us for our next video where
we're gonna start talking
about authorization.