Hey there, welcome back to
this module on ASP.NET Core,
my name is Jeff Fritz
>> And I'm Jon Galloway.
>> And, we're gonna talk
a little in this module about,
authentication and
authorization security, right?
>> Right, right, so there's a
lot in there let's get started.
I'm creating a new
ASP NET Core application.
And one of the things on
the dialog here is, it has this
thing on the right, where it
says change authentication.
So that said, no authentication.
That means, the application
is completely anonymous.
>> Right, anybody can access it.
>> Right, exactly.
So what we're gonna be
showing in this section,
we're gonna be looking at
individual user accounts.
There are some others available.
You can do Windows
authentication, for
an intranet application.
>> So that would use
internal Windows challenge
capabilities with IIS, so it can
check with Active Directory, and
make sure that folks
are logged in.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
>> All that magical IIS
intranet stuff.
There's also school accounts and
this all set out.
This works with active
directory O365, and
it has support for cloud, single
and multiple organizations.
So kinda the simplest one, and
I think kinda the most standard
that a lot of people use is
individual user accounts.
>> Okay.
>> This is kind of a good
place to get started.
And you have some options here,
storing your accounts in app
actually uses local databases-
>> Okay.
>> For
storing there the information.
And where you can also
connect this to stool in
the cloud, right?
>> Sure.
>> So that's one nice thing is,
you can develop for a while, and
then you can migrate over later.
>> Very good.
>> So we're going to do this,
store user account in app.
So I'll click OK,
and get started.
So the first thing we're going
to be looking at in here once we
start this up,
is that our authentication
is set up using middleware.
So like just about everything
in ASP NET core now,
it's all configured
in middleware.
So if I go to my startup, we'll
see if we scroll down a bit,
we have in here use identity.
So this is actually
the service is configured to
use the identity service, with
default token providers, etc.
We'll be configuring more
of those in a second.
And then down in here,
it says app.UseAuthentication.
So that's kinda
what turns it on.
>> And it's there inside of our
configure method between
static files and UseMvc.
So that we're not authenticating
access to the static files.
>> Exactly.
>> But we are gonna check for
authentication requirements for
npc pages.
>> Exactly, that's a very key
point, that this middleware kind
of falls there,
it goes top to bottom.
So, it'll get called
in that order.
So, I'll want my static files,
CSS, etc, for
my log in pages, right?
>> Sure.
>> That's important.
So just right out of the box,
I'm going to run
this application.
And then, we'll go through and
we'll start configuring
some things in here.
So, when I run this,
first of all,
some of the things I'm going to
be doing with my application,
I'm gonna be later setting
up OAuth for login,
and that's gonna require SSL,
the way OAuth is
setup to call backs to my
application require SSL.
Fortunately, Visual Studio and
IS kind of do this for
me automatically.
So what this is doing is it's
saying, I can create an IS SSL
certificate for you, and install
it locally on your machine.
For development this is
a real easy way to go.
So I'm gonna say, okay, and
I'm gonna memorize that show
one thumbprint, just kidding.
[LAUGH].
I'm gonna install
the certificate.
So this certificate is installed
locally on my machine.
>> Okay.
>> What that allows me to do,
is run my application locally,
you'll see in the address bar
that it actually does say,
get this out of here, https.
So that allows me to kind of
right from the beginning of my
development, start
testing with SSL locally.
>> Okay.
>> So the first thing
that I'm gonna do,
is register a new user.
And I'm doing this with
individual user accounts.
The very simplest
way to do this,
is just create an email and
password.
So, just create something.
And there are some default
password requirements,
need a capital letter, etc.
And those are configurable.
And they need to match.
Let me try that again.
There we go.
So it is nice that it at
least checks that for me.
>> No.
>> No, it blew up.
This is actually expected.
The first time through that I
ran this, and the reason is,
it needs to store my
identity data somewhere.
>> Right.
>> And
it's using Entity Framework for
that.
So this is actually
the first time through,
that I access this.
It's saying I need to create
those tables for you.
>> So
it's gonna create those tables,
in what kind of a database for
me?
>> So
this is in my local SQL express.
>> Got you, the local DB.
>> Yeah, local DB center, yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Exactly, so
now I hit apply migrations and
this is creating that
database for me.
>> So, this error screen
is entity framework saying,
we don't have all the database
definitions created
inside that database.
Hey press this button to apply and-
>> Exactly.
>> Do those updates.
>> So,
this is the migration that runs,
it creates those, it actually
is all ready finished and
it says,
try refreshing the page.
So I'm gonna refresh
the page fortunately for
me, it reset the form
when I refresh the page,
it refreshes so I don't need
to type that password again.
So great, there I've gone
through and logged in.
>> And it says,
hello test at test.com.
>> Exactly.
>> Cool, okay.
>> So
let's configure that a bit.
So, I'm going to go in, and I
am going to click on my account.
I will see in here, I can change
my email, or phone number.
I can do things like send
a verification email.
I could, update my password.
>> Sure.
>> What I want to
show here though,
is configuring two-factor
authentication.
And two-factor authentication
is really important.
This is a great feature to
enable for your applications.
The reason is,
if someone gets my password
they can take over my
account very easily.
However, if I setup
two-factor authentication
on my phone, using a two
factor authentication application-
>> Yes.
>> Then someone would need both
my password, and my phone.
>> Sure.
>> And so,
it's just adding a second factor
of authentication for me.
So if I click on here and
I say, add authenticator app,
this is going to take me to
a page, and it's gonna tell me,
hey, you could go in, you could
type in this code, and this
code is actually a seed for a
time based TOTP password thing,
where it regenerates a password,
every I believe, 30 seconds.
>> Okay.
>> Now, we'll look at that
in a second, but your users,
this isn't the best
experience to make them,
type this key into their phone.
>> No.
>> Most two factor of,
is set up on phone, and
I don't want them
to have to do that.
>> Sure.
>> So, a nice way to kinda
get this information
over on to my phone,
is using a QR code.
>> Okay.
>> So,
there's actually some pretty
good documentation on here, and
we're just gonna follow through
what they're telling us to do.
And it's actually,
surprisingly, easy.
>> Good.
>> So yeah, so
what we're doing for this,
is we're actually using a Java
Script library that is going
to generate a QR code for me.
>> Okay.
>> So you can add this
to your application,
any number of different ways.
I'm going to do
this using bower,
just cuz bower is
currently set up.
But, you could use
any kind of bundling,
you could use You know you could
just download the file into your
directory if you wanted to.
So this is qr-js, and
I'm just going to pick star,
there's just one version of it.
And we'll save that.
And so then that's going
to dump this file into,
procure, that's now
the secure code JS.
So you just need to put it
somewhere in your dub dub dub
root and know where you put it.
>> So you made an update
to Bower JSON.
>> Mm-hm.
>> You included the qrcode-js
line, and
in the background, Visual Studio
kicked off a Bower install and
it wrote the contents of
that package into that
qrcode-js folder inside of the
lib sub folder of dub dub root.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
>> And
it's important to note,
[LAUGH] Bower
was kind of a preferred way of
installing packages for a while.
It's kind of going away.
Bower is still maintained but
it's not kind of
the recommended way really-
>> Okay.
>> To get libraries
going forward.
So, you'll see this probably
change in the future.
But the important point here
really is get this library and
put it in your dub dub dub root.
[LAUGH].
>> Okay.
>> So now what we're going to do
is we're going to look in our
pages account manage enable
authenticator view so
I go to pages account.
Manage, Enable Authenticator.
So, and again,
that was that spelled out for
me right here in the docs.
Next, I'm going to scroll down
to the bottom of the script
section and
I'm going to paste this.
And the important thing
here is to make sure
that my path to this
script is correct.
And I wanna put this below my
ValidationScriptsPartial, okay?
So all I'm doing here is putting
in the script that is going to
enable generating
client side qrCode.
So now,
I'm actually gonna go here and
I'll take advantage of
Visual Studio's auto complete.
And auto complete
completes that for me and
I know it's gonna work.
Right so now that that's there,
I'll run this again.
And we'll see when
we go to that page.
Well actually, when we go
to enable two factor auth.
So if I say,
configure authenticator app.
Now, this is my QR code.
>> Fancy.
>> Yeah, so that QR code
just makes an easy way for
me to get this data
onto my phone.
>> Okay.
>> So
the next step that I
would do is actually,
on my phone I would
take a snapshot.
I would go into my
authenticator app and
I would scan this QR code and
it'll say great,
added and it'll do all
the magic registration.
>> It'll start
generating codes for me.
>> Yep.
Now, because we wanna kind of go
through and show how this works,
I'm actually going to use
a test online authenticator app
that can do this for me.
>> Okay.
>> So if I go in here and
I copy this code, this is
something you might want to
do just in development in order
to kind of make sure that your
two factor auth is working.
>> And then you don't
end up polluting your
personal authenticator on your
phone with all these test codes.
>> Exactly, exactly.
So I can call this
whatever I want.
MVA 2FA, and
then I paste in this secret key.
This secret key is kind of
the seed that's going to create
these two factor auth numbers
that I'm gonna actually type in.
>> So there's my six
digit number I would use
to authenticate.
>> Exactly.
So now what I need
to do is go into,
now you watch, see that just
rolled over every 30 seconds.
>> Yeah.
>> So
now I need to go into this and
I need to give it my off code.
Once I do this it verifies
it and it says great,
two factor auth is set up.
>> Cool.
Now what are these?
>> Well,
what happens if I lose my phone?
>> Or get a new phone,
or whatever?
>> Right, you drop it in
a stream or something, my gosh.
>> Exactly.
So, what they do for
this is they give me
these recovery keys.
So these recovery keys
are something I can use, and
I recommend putting
these in a secure place.
>> Those are two columns
of five keys, right?
>> Total of ten keys.
>> Okay.
>> Yup so
these are keys that you
want to keep these, but
you want to keep them
somewhere secure.
>> Sure.
>> Somewhere secret and
somewhere secure.
So now let's log out and
log in and
this time we'll see
using two factor auth.
So I'm gonna hit log in.
I'm gonna type in test, and
we'll see if I can
type my password.
>> You gotta get past that first
factor authentication before we
get to the second.
No!
>> There it is.
>> All right.
>> It requires an uppercase,
a number and-
>> Special character?
>> Special character.
Yeah.
So now, it says what's
your authenticator code?
Now I would go on to my phone
and I would look up my app that
I just registered and
it'll give me a number.
So in this case, I'm going
to my pretend phone and
I look here and I see this is
my two factor auth number,
my authenticator code.
So I'll hit that.
Now, what I would normally want
to do is say remember on this
machine.
I'd likely want to do
that because I don't
want to necessarily have to
type that in every single time.
>> And you're in.
>> I'm in.
Now let's look one more time and
we'll see what happens.
Let's see if I can maybe
type my password this time.
>> [LAUGH]
>> I should've
saved my password? Okay.
So now, no, my phone exploded
into a thousand pieces,
what am I gonna do?
So now I'm gonna
actually go in here and
say log in using
a recovery code.
So I can grab one of these and
what I recommend doing
is actually delete it.
So I did CTRL + X.
>> These are one time use?
>> They're one time use.
>> Okay.
>> Once I use that thing
then it's gone.
So then I'll go in here and
go Log in.
And now,
my two factor auth worked.
>> Okay.
>> And what you can do,
if you want to at that point,
is you can actually go
reset recovery codes.
>> And get a new
collection of ten codes.
>> So now it regenerated
all those old codes that I
generated, those are all
worthless now, so
I'm just gonna paste those over.
And you can put this in, you
know, say a OneDrive, OneNote,
somewhere secure though,
because someone gets these,
they can bypass your
two factor auth.
>> Absolutely.
>> So let's kind of
review what we did here.
We went in and
we first saw the different
options that are available.
We looked in our startup, and
we saw kind of how things
are configured, and
that use authentication kind
of is already wired up for me.
And this stuff about
token providers and
stuff that's already there.
Then we went in,
created a basic account, and
then we went in and
did our authentication.
Now, one other thing,
one other kind of minor thing,
but, there's the thing
in there that says,
hey here's how you can create.
The first time when you go in
and you set up two factor auth,
there's a little note there that
says, here's how to enable it.
>> I think it was under
Configure Authenticator app?
>> Configure Authenticator app,
that's it.
So here,
you'll delete this line.
>> Sure, we don't wanna
ship that instruction.
>> Yeah, exactly.
But that's basically it.
So this is pretty sophisticated,
this will allow you to keep your
customer's application secure.
Yeah, pretty great.
>> Cool.
All right, I hope you come back
and join us in a little bit.
We're gonna take a look at
more authentication options in
the next video.