Hi, I'm Jon Galloway.
>> And I'm Jeff Fritz.
>> And we've been talking about
logging into an application,
setting up simple identity.
So this is both setting up,
registering a user.
>> Sure.
>> And then also enabling two
factor authentication, so
that we make sure my password.
Somebody can't just take my
password and login to the site.
>> Sure, you're authenticating
somewhere else.
Maybe it's Twitter,
a Microsoft account, Facebook. Sure.
>> Exactly, so
now that we've got that setup,
what can we do with it?
>> Sure, we wanna look now at,
how do I grant folks access
to specific features?
Right, we've gone
through authentication.
Are you the person
you say you are?
Let's now look at authorization.
Hey John,
are you allowed to access these
features of my application?
>> Great.
>> So let's take a look
here on my machine.
I got a sample already started
up here with a couple of
features already built,
just to get us through some of
the boiler plate capabilities.
So this is a new application,
a new ASP.NET Core
2.0 application.
And I've already got my identity
configuration in my start
of class here, but
I've changed my database to use
the InMemoryDatabase and I've
just called it off the sample.
>> So the InMemoryDatabase is a
great way for working with test
data or something that you wanna
have created every time you
start up your application?
>> Yup, every time I start,
let's rebuild that database.
Consequently, I need to also put
some seed data in that database
every time I start up.
So down here in my configure
method, I added a call into
something that I called
SampleData to initialize that
database and I'm passing in
the application services.
That's a reference to
the dependency injection
provider that we have.
So I'll go over into that
SampleData method and
I want you to see I'm actually
using the same things that we
have in our register page
to create a new user.
So I first have to reach in and
get a service scope for
my dependency
injection provider and
I have to call get required
service IServiceScopeFactory.
So this is the reference
to the exact version,
the current context that I need
to create objects from that
dependency injection provider.
>> Okay.
>> So now that I have that,
I can start saying GetService.
>> Okay, so just to make sure
that it does make sense to me
and everyone else, the ideas
you're gonna be working with
services and things to provide,
like for instance
the user management, those who
are to service logging also.
>> Right.
>> So you need to talk to
the service scope factory, you
need to get the current service
scope, so that you can
work with those services.
>> Right, I'm working around
the way we would do constructor
injection in our other classes
because I'm interacting with
that provider directly.
>> Okay.
>> And
I need to declare my scope
that I'm working in.
So I'm gonna get a reference
to the hosting environment and
if I'm not in development mode,
don't do any of this
initialization.
I then grab a reference
to the role manager and
I wanna start creating roles.
And this is important, you need
to have roles in your database
if you're going to
assign folks to a role.
So I create two roles,
one called admin and
one called power users.
I wait for
those to finish being created.
And then I'm going to log some
information to the console that
I accurately added those roles.
Next, I get access to
our user manager, and
this is what happens inside
of our register CSS HTML.
So in the normal flow of things
when someone registers as a new
user, we create a new
application user with their user
name and email equal to whatever
email address was keyed in.
And we say user manager
create that user with this
incoming user, and then
whatever password was keyed in.
So when sample did a class here,
I'm gonna do that
exact same thing.
I create a new application
user within default email and
user name, jeff@test.com.
It's easier to remember
something for me to test with.
And then I'm gonna create that
user with this very very super
secret, highly secure
password that uses uppercase,
lower case, a number and
special character.
>> No one can ever crack that.
>> No body can ever crack that. Okay-
>> [LAUGH]
>> And then I'm gonna log that
information just so
that I am aware of that and
I can see that in my console.
>> Okay, so
a couple of things here.
One that I like is, well,
you are kind of having to
write some custom code.
You're continuing to work with
the providers, the user manager,
all those things that the rest
of the application works.
So you're not like cheating or
hacking around in there.
>> No, no.
>> And what's nice is your code
will continue to work maybe as
the user manager gets
bug fixes or whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> Another thing,
just you've got a password
where you're showing this here,
obviously we talked about in
other session where we use
things like the secret storage
and that kind of thing, right?
>> Yes.
>> So this is an example to show
we're creating a password in
line, but you will pull that out
of secret storage or something.
>> Sure, that you could
absolutely put these things into
configuration somewhere, so
that you pull it in from that
location and then it's only
saved on your machine.
>> Okay.
>> This is development mode,
this is a sample.
I want you to see these things,
so that it's a little bit
clearer where the values
are coming from.
>> Okay.
>> So I'm going to go from here
and go into my solution explorer
and I want to show you one last
thing before I get started,
and that is inside
of my project file.
I have a call here on line 12,
I'm adding a new tool into
the mix here called
the DotNet.Watcher, okay?
>> Okay.
>> DotNet.Watcher is a feature
that we can use on the command
line to watch our application,
and as C# files change,
automatically recompile and
rerun whatever command
we passed into it.
What this will let us do is,
as we go through this excercise,
and you can use then when
you're writing your code,
is you can execute
all of your code,
as you type it in and
save it, it'll rebuild and
you can revisit the website and
see those changes immediately.
>> Kind of the same experience
I get when I'm editing
my razor views.
Where those are picked up
immediately this doing that with
your C# code.
>> Absolutely.
So let me kick that off and
let's at the website
the way it is right now.
So I'm going to start
a command prompt and
I'm going to jump
into that folder.
This is identity
authorization sample.
All right, and
now I can use that watch
command by saying dotnet watch.
And then what I wanted
to actually execute
when there is a change.
And I'm gonna say
execute the run command.
So now the watch has started,
it's going to do its
build operation here, and
start running and
hosting my application.
So there we go.
It's running the application and
you see here the log information
that I told it to write out.
Added the admin and
power users roles,
created our test user with
that super secure password.
And it's listening on local
host 52764, so let me copy that
and I will go over to my browser
and navigate to that location.
And there's my application,
okay?
I can click login and
I will login with jeff@test.com
with my password.
And I'm logged in,
don't save my password.
And I get my user name
appearing here on the top right
>> Okay, cool.
>> This is where we left off.
>> That's the same as
if you had gone in and
clicked register basically-
>> Absolutely.
>> That's done that encode.
>> Yep, we've done that encode,
we've got it saved in memory So
that we can jump through and
do some testing here, and
learn a little bit now about
authorization now that we've
made authentication really easy
and in test mode, if you will.
>> Okay.
>> Okay, so now,
let's go back to my code.
And let's start preventing
access to some things.
I'm gonna go over
to the About page.
So here's pages, and
I'll go to the About page.
Now, this is the code that we
would be showing on the page
when I navigate to it,
when I click there, I see this.
Well, what if I want to require
folks to be logged in in order
to access that page?
What you can do is you go in
your Razor Page page model, and
you can decorate this class
with the authorize attribute.
>> Okay.
>> So this says users must
be authorized to access this
with no other information,
they just have to be authorized,
they have to be authenticated.
We don't really need to
know more information.
>> Just anyone that's
logged into my site?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> So I will save that change.
And if you look over here,
you'll see this is what
the watch is doing for me.
It sees that a file changed,
it recompiled, and
it is re-running my application.
>> Yeah.
>> So, now, if I click
the About page, It's not
going to the About page,
it went to the login page.
And if you look up
here in the top, right?
It says account login
return URL is About.
So it's saying you weren't
allowed to access this, and
it routed me over here to
show this content instead.
You have to log in, and then
we'll take you back over there.
And this is all wired up for
me, so that when I key in that
information, it does take me
back to the page I requested.
>> Okay.
>> So the Authorize
attribute lets us get in and
access those appropriate things.
But that's just if folks
are logged in, right?
We have a role out there
called administrator.
Maybe I wanna protect this
page and say you know what,
only administrators
are allowed to access this.
>> Okay, so this is why we go
in and change only admin kind of
[CROSSTALK] inventory or
whatever.
>> Yes,
if this was admin features,
we want to restrict that.
What you can do now is enhance
that Authorize attribute, and
you can say roles equals.
And then specify the names of
the roles that you must have in
order to access this.
>> Got it.
>> So I will say you must be
an admin to access this page.
And now, if I go back and
I refresh this.
Access denied.
You don't have access
to this resource.
So this actually the Access
denied page, and it's got some
boilerplate information here
to say you don't have access.
>> Okay.
>> Not bad, okay.
But how do I make sure that
folks have access to this role,
that they're members of this
role when they're being created?
So let me grant access to the
admin role to my Jeff test user.
So I'll go back into
my sample data.
Now, if you are using the
register facilities that we have
here and using identity, you
would need to build some sort of
a page to manage
access to roles, and
grant users access
to different roles.
But you would use pretty
much the same feature here,
where you would say
userManager.AddToRole.
And then I specify the user
that I'm adding to that role.
So I'm gonna specify user
because that's my Jeff test
user here.
And then I can give it
the name of the role that I
want to add them to.
So Admin.
And now, you know what, let's
throw in await in front of that.
Much better.
So now it's gonna recompile, and
I should be able to come back
here, refresh this page, and
actually see my About page
again because Jeff is an admin.
>> Nice.
>> Not yet.
He has to log out and
log back in.
>> Okay.
>> It's added, Those roles are
added when you are logged in.
So About, and
now I can get into the page.
>> Okay.
>> Because I'm now
a member of that role.
>> Great.
>> Okay?
>> Okay.
>> So roles are pretty easy.
That's a pretty standard thing
that people can get their
arms around.
They're familiar with roles
in their operating system.
They've seen using roles
in applications before, so
it's a pretty common concept
to add users to a role.
>> Something like an admin role.
>> Exactly.
Or- >> Content manager role.
>> Yes.
>> Or whatever it is.
>> Editor of my website.
So, what if you wanna actually
work directly with specific
claims about a user, right?
These are those user
properties that for
a security concern
you want to know.
>> Okay.
>> Okay?
So perhaps we need to enforce
and say, you know what?
We know there's rules in Canada
where only Canadians can access
certain features of
an application, right?
They have rules in Canada around
Government data must be hosted
on government servers.
>> A lot of countries/regions do that.
>> Yes.
>> So, what if we wanna
enforce that only Canadians
can access this page?
So that means we need to create
what is called a policy,
not just a role but a policy
that we're gonna enforce on
a specific claim being
present with a certain value.
>> Okay.
>> So let's take a look at that.
So I'm gonna come
back into my code,
I'm gonna go over to
the start up page.
And now, inside of my configure
services, I'm gonna add
some capabilities now to define
these additional policies.
>> So, what we do is we
call AddAuthorization.
And then we can start
to configure policies.
So let's add an initial policy,
Called CanadiansOnly.
Okay?
And what we can do then is
specify about the policy,
That the policy,
Requires a specific claim.
And then we need to name that
claim that we're going to
check on.
So, I'll say ClaimTypes.Country.
>> So there's some predefined
claim types, then?
>> Yeah, these are standard
claim types that are available
to you under the claim
types enumeration.
And there's all kinds
of things in here.
If they're anonymous, their
country/region, their date of birth.
There's some web applications
that you need to be a certain
age in order to access features,
particularly around the alcohol
industry in United States.
>> Sure.
>> There's one example.
>> Yeah.
So those are predefined ones,
but I can also do just a string
there, as well,
I can [CROSSTALK] okay, great.
>> You're absolutely right.
So let me key in Country.
Now, at this point it's just
requiring the presence of
a country/region claim.
I wanna specify a specific
country/region, so I can comma and
key in an array of
required values, or
just a specific
value that I want.
So I'm going to specify Canada.
>> Okay.
>> So now,
I have a policy called
CanadiansOnly, and
you're required to
be from Canada.
So if I save that,
that policy is being built and
added in by my .NET watcher.
Let me go back over
to my About page, and
where I specified
roles equals admin,
what I can now do is I
can say policy equals.
And I'm gonna make sure
I copy this correctly.
My CanadiansOnly policy name,
I'll copy that string,
paste it in here, and save.
And now my Jeff user
isn't a Canadian.
>> No.
>> My Jeff user is an admin, but
not a Canadian.
So, he shouldn't be able
to access this page.
So I will login as Jeff And
while you're doing that,
I think it's good to
point out there we moved
from a specific role to
a policy and people I've
talked to have said policy-based
is kinda the way to go, right?
>> Yes.
>> You wanna move towards claims
and policies because they're
much more configurable and
you're not, this person's in
this role or this person,
it's a lot more rich the kind
of information you get back.
>> A lot of flexibility in
there in how you configure your
policy.
>> Okay.
>> So I'm logged in as Jeff
again and when I click About,
I don't have access
to this resource.
>> And you're not Canadian.
>> Even though it's an admin.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm not Canadian and
can't access it.
So how do we grant those
claims to our user?
So I'll come back into
my sample data and
I will add that
claim to my user.
So Add, and I will add
a claim asynchronously,
I specify the user and then
that claim that I am creating.
And so
the type was ClaimTypes,Country.
And the name of that
country is Canada.
So I'll Save that and
now I'm adding Jeff and
his Canadian citizenship
to my application.
I'll go back over to my website,
I will click Log out,
because I wanna Log in and
make sure that I received
that claim information.
>> Sure.
>> So
now I am logging in as Jeff.
So I'm logged in, and
let me click the About page.
And now I'm granted access.
>> Okay.
>> So I have that claim, I have
access to an admin role, but
it was only the Canadian
claim that I
needed in order to
get access to this.
>> Mm-hm.
But realistically,
there's scenarios where
a global admin needs
access to these things that
Canadians have access to.
>> Right.
>> So
what if I wanna enforce and
say you ca be an admin or
a Canadian to access this-
>> You just need one of those
two things.
>> You just need one,
you need that or, right?
What we can do is we can create
a little bit more complex
requirement in code with
the requirement class.
Now, I've already written
out this class for us and
it's sitting over here inside
of my Requirements folder
called Canadian Requirement.
Now this class, it inherits from
the AuthorizationHandler of type
CanadianRequirement, cuz
we're gonna
handle the authorization for
this requirement.
And it's
an IAuthorizationRequirement.
That interface and that abstract
class requires this one method.
HandleRequirementAsync, and
let me carriage return here, so
we can see everything.
And that receives a context, and
then that requirement
we're checking.
So here's where I'm
doing that or check.
If the user is in role admin,
>> Mm-hm.
>> Then they've succeeded
at this requirement.
If they have
the claim Country and
that claim is Canada,
they've succeeded also.
And then Task.CompletedTask.
>> Great, so if I get to the end
of this task completed and
I haven't matched either of
those, then it's gonna fail out?
>> Right,
by default a requirement fails.
>> Okay.
>> So now I can enforce
this requirement by saying,
by creating a policy called
Canadians or Admins.
So let's create that
policy real quick here.
>> And you're just
adding another policy so
your existing CanadiansOnly
policy is still in effect-
>> Absolutely.
>> So you can have
multiple policies and
you just stack them up.
>> You just keep stacking
them up, you're right.
>> So I'm gonna say,
policy.AddRequirements,
and I'm gonna say new-
>> And
you'll pass that class then,
right, okay.
>> CanadianRequirement.
Okay, now that's a class,
I could pass in constructor
arguments, I could configure
it however I want-
>> Mm-hm.
>> Maybe I wanna just have
a nationality requirement and
I wanna pass in not just Canada.
Maybe I wanna pass in instead,
United States and
have an American requirement.
>> Mm-hm.
>> You can do that also.
>> Okay.
>> But for this, that's
a very simple configuration.
And now I can use that same
policy if I go back over
to my About page.
And I can change that,
and it will now enforce.
You can be a Canadian or
an Admin and
be able to access this page.
>> And I'm guessing those could
be that policy attribute,
those could be common to
limited or something, right?
>> Yes.
>> I can put
in a list of policies.
>> Absolutely.
>> Okay.
>> So
now I'm gonna take away
my Canadian citizenship.
>> All right, it's been revoked.
Rough day for you.
>> Rough day, man.
So now I'll log out and
log back in.
And I click About and
I can access the page.
>> Cuz you're an admin.
>> Because I'm an admin.
But one final thing
that we should do.
It's kind of bad form
to show that About link
if you can't access it.
>> Right, it's just mean.
>> It's rude, right?
>> [LAUGH]
>> It's not being
a good citizen.
>> And that's pretty common.
Once I log into
a site as an admin,
I'll see new links up here.
>> Absolutely.
>> Yeah.
>> So what you can do to enforce
those checks, and show and
hide features on your page.
I'm gonna go into my layout,
where that About link exists,
and I'm going to inject
a feature here that will allow
me to check for authorization.
So I'm going to inject
the IAuthorizationService
and I will just call this
AuthorizationService.
I'm gonna want
a using statement,
there to make sure that
Microsoft.AspNetCore,
to make sure that it-
>> That you can call the-
>> That I can call it, yep.
So there we go,
my AuthorizationService
is highlighted cuz I have
the appropriate using statement.
And now I can go down
to my About, and
I can hide that by just wrapping
it with a normal if statement.
So if, and I will say, await AuthorizationService.Authoerize-
Async.
And I'm gonna check
the current user
against the CanadiansOrAdmin
policy,
all right, let me just
verify that policy name,
nope, it's CanadianOrAdmin,
all right.
And if, I need to check
to see if that succeeded,
if it did then we will
show the About link.
>> Great.
>> All right,
let me go back over to my page,
I'm not logged in, and I'll
Refresh and my About is gone.
Because I don't have-
>> You haven't logged in.
>> Exactly, I'm not logged in,
I'm not an admin and
I'm not Canadian.
If I log in now, And
now I have the About link.
>> Yes, okay.
>> I can click it and it works.
So, I have that complete
experience of granting and
revoking access to this page.
And now, I can also grant and
revoke visibility to these links
to these pages by using that
AuthorizationService inside
of my Razor views.
>> Okay, so
I wanna take you back aways.
And so, we looked at doing all
this in code during app startup.
We configure the user,
we created you as a user-
>> Yep.
>> In code and
we added you to the role.
What if I wanted to say,
during the registration process,
maybe I've got a drop down where
I collect the user's country/region,
>> Yep.
>> Right, so, what I am hoping
is, because you have used
the user manager and all those
kind of services, you could do
that same kind of logic during
the registration process?
>> Absolutely, so where I called
AddToRoleAsync, or AddClaimAsync
here inside of my sample data
that I was initializing.
I could certainly
copy those out and
paste them here into
my registration page.
Where it's actually going and
creating that user sending
those email confirmations.
I could put those
modifications in here, so
that we enhance that user's
profile information.
As they're being created.
>> Perfect, okay, so
let me try and wrap up all
the stuff you covered.
>> Sure.
>> Because it was quite a bit.
>> It was.
>> Okay, so we started at the
beginning in session where we
had just set up simple identity.
I'm able to authenticate a user.
>> Correct, yes.
>> So now I know who that user
is, but I haven't done anything
to restrict what they can do or
can see.
>> Yep.
>> Then you showed how to use
those services to create
a user end code and
to assign them to a role.
>> Yep.
>> And then after that you
showed how to assign policies
and to kind of turn
those policies on for
specific views and
say you can only see this thing.
You can only click on this link.
If you are in a role or
have meta policy and you defined
a custom policy that kind of
took it to the next level.
>> A custom requirement kind of
gave us the ability to write
some code beyond just
a simple string match of
the word Canada or Admin, right?
I could do more complex testing
like that date of birth,
I could test to see if those
folks were over 21 today, and
then allow them access.
>> Great, wow.
>> So that's all we did here,
and so that's the story.
>> Thanks for joining us.
I hope you'll stick around for
the next video where we'll
continue digging
into ASP.NET Core.