Hey friends,
we just successfully survived
the creation of a web API.
>> [LAUGH] Yes, we did.
>> Entirely from scratch,
that was pretty cool.
>> Yeah.
>> We got get and get post,
put and delete, create,
read, update, and delete.
>> Yep.
>> We made our little concert
ticket management application
here, but
it has no documentation.
And there's really no good
API way, there's no WSDL,
the Web Services
Description Language-
>> Yeah.
>> For our thing.
So how can I fix this?
>> So what we can do is we can
actually add on the Swagger capability-
>> Swagger.
>> That will
describe our API for
folks that aren't
familiar with it.
>> Okay,
Swagger sounds pretty cool.
What is Swagger?
>> So Swagger is a standard that
folks use to define their API's,
so that those restful end points
can be found, discovered, and
executed easily with a little
bit of documentation.
And even a helpful interface you
can use to interact with it if
you enable that feature
on your website.
>> Okay, so it's a description
language for the web API.
>> Yep.
>> And then, at that point,
anyone, even people who
aren't using .NET, of course,
can call that API.
So a client, a Ruby client,
a Python client, a JavaScript
client can then consume that
Swagger, be ready to generate if
they choose, or absorb if
they don't, that API's shape.
>> Yep, they can learn about it
and generate that strongly typed
API if they need it or they
can interact with it directly,
just like we were
doing using Postman.
>> All right, cool, so
there is a library,
an open source library,
called Swashbuckle.
>> Yes.
>> Like a swashbuckling pirate.
That Swaggers, I assume, and
that allows you to
add this Swagger.
Now, Swagger is not a Microsoft
thing, Swagger is a thing.
>> It's an open source thing.
So I'm gonna go here into
Visual Studio, this is
the same one that we were
working on just moments ago.
So I'm gonna click on
Solution Explorer, and I'm gonna
right-click on Dependencies and
say Manage NewGet Packages.
And I'm gonna click
here on Browse and
we're gonna search for
Swashbuckle.
And I want specifically
the ASP.NET Core version of
Swashbuckle.
And this is interesting, notice
that it said no packages found,
you might bump into
this sometimes.
There is a packet source
pull down here that,
you might have different
packet sources,
you wanna make sure that
you're picking the right one.
Sometimes that happens to me.
So Swashbuckle, there we go,
went by too fast,
swashbuckle.aspnetcore.
There's different ones for
different versions.
There we go,
probably the right one,
it's got a lot of
great downloads.
All right, gonna hit the latest
stable one, and hit install.
That's gonna then go and
get those packages.
And that's all done.
Cool, so those were added.
Now remember, when we were
in startup earlier, and
we did our services, we added
MVC, we added our DbContext.
Swashbuckle is one
of those things.
It's a service that
we're gonna go and add.
So I'm gonna say
services.AddSwaggerGen,
Swagger generation, right?
We're gonna go and
make a little room for that,
cuz I'm gonna put some
things inside SwaggerGen.
All right, let's go and
do our SwaggerGen and
pass in this other object and
we're gonna say,
we're gonna need documentation,
let's say that this is maybe v1,
and we're gonna make a new Info.
Now here I've gotta choice,
I wanna point this out,
you see I typed in Info, and
it's saying, do you mean Swashbuckle.ASPNetCore.Swagger.-
Info?
I'm gonna hit control dot and
add that using, so
I don't have to fill that out so
much.
And then the title, there's
the different options, you see?
TermsOfService for your API,
and titles and descriptions.
We'll just take title.
>> All those things that your
API consumers might to know
about your API.
>> Exactly, and we'll just
say it's a Concert API,
keep it that, okay?
All right, that's just
the setting up of that initial
Swagger, Okay?
And then down here in Configure,
we've got UseMvc and
all that kind of stuff.
Let's give it a UI.
This lets it answer the call,
basically, when someone goes and
asks for Swagger, but I wanna
see an attractive UI for this.
>> Right, that AddSwaggerGen, it
adds that extra information, so
that it knows that
swagger information is in
the dependency
injection container.
>> Right.
>> So then down here-
>> We use it.
>> We can put it in
the pipeline, the HTTP pipeline.
>> Al right, and
I'm gonna say UseSwagger itself,
that enables it now.
So now it exists and
it can listen.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you, I misspoke before.
And then we can say
UseSwaggerUI, okay?
And then here,
we'll give a little bit of
hints on how we wanna do that.
So UseSwaggerUI, So
I thought that would,
is that correct?
All right, let's try this again.
So UseSwaggerUI,
SwaggerEndpoint and
its gonna be at
swagger/v1/swagger.json,
and well call it
a Ticket API V1.
All right,
Sometimes I get a little
confused with these lambdas.
>> Yeah, all the different,
there we go.
>> There we go, so
let's go into a build.
And now I know that this is
where the Swagger's going to be.
>> Right,
the definition of our API, so
let's go and run this and see.
What's nice about this, though,
is you'll notice we did it
all inside of the Startup.cs.
We didn't have to
go into our API.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, so the Swashbuckle
tool, what it's gonna do?
What Swashbuckle the value that
it adds is it's going to go and
explore that API and
generate this UI automatically.
Gonna I paced in, swagger.json.
Now, I'm doing this in Microsoft Edge,
which is a lovely browser,
but not well known for
attractive json handling.
So I'm gonna pull that
over into Chrome,
where we have an extension.
So this isn't the API,
this is the Swagger for the API.
>> This is the documentation.
>> The documentation.
>> Yeah.
>> It's the description,
it's the shape.
So for example,
I can close this up.
Look /ticket has a get.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Right?
Takes an array,
post takes in an API ticket.
Ticket/id, that's a get,
there's your delete, right?
We still got values along for
the ride, remember?
>> Sure, look at that.
>> That's pretty cool.
>> And check out the producer's
entry there, right?
If I go to API values,
I can get plain text,
I can get json
coming out of there.
>> Yeah.
>> Not just json.
>> So
how do I got UI from my Swagger?
>> So that's actually at
a slightly different end point
if you just go to,
I believe it's just /swagger.
>> Okay.
>> There you go.
>> There it is,
I see, I love this.
I just got a free API for
my ticket.
And notice I've got my v1,
I could have v2, v3, etc.
>> Exactly.
>> You've got values which
we kind of kept around
from earlier, right?
We've got our gets.
Here's the part that
I think is fun,
you can poke at these things,
right?
I can say try it out.
They'll tell you how to
try it out with a curl
at the command line.
The URL and they're giving you,
effectively, a tester inside
of your documentation.
So imagine if you're gonna
ship that documentation
to your customer, how they'll
feel pretty good about that.
>> It is everything that we
looked at in Postman, but
we generated this from
our application and
it's in the browser for
anybody regardless of what
tool they have installed.
>> So here's a tester, I'll just
say I want Id 1 to write out and
I just went and
got the Beyonce concert.
>> There you go.
>> That's link,
so that is called Swagger,
the concept, Swashbuckle
is the implementation of
Swagger for APS.NET Core.
And there is a bunch of
great documentation on this,
we're gonna find that.
>> If you go to
docs.microsoft.com?
>> Okay, there it is, ASP.NET.
>> Right, and
if you look up Swagger there?
>> I want this one.
>> There you go, yep.
>> ASP.NET Core Web API
Help Pages using Swagger.
Walking through step
by step by step.
And what's nice about this
docs as with all of our docs,
Visual Studio for Mac, Visual
Studio Code from the command
line, explained to you
how to do all of this.
You can see exactly how we
add it to the middleware,
how we configured it,
what you get, and
then you can get into
the customization.
You can go and
add version information.
You can add your license,
you can add your terms
of service and move on.
And even from there, if you
want, you can go and bring that
up into Azure and we have tools
that will suck that Swagger in.
And if you have a Swagger
enabled Web API,
you'll be able to then
use the API management
features in Azure to
even do more with that.
>> Yep, to manage,
you'll be able to see
all your documentation.
And the other folks that
are using your end point will be
able to see that documentation.
>> Exactly, you can also
modify that Swagger.
So in this example here,
what Shayne has got in, change
the CSS to put documentation and
then the looks they way he
wants his part to look.
>> Maybe you want your
logo in the corner,
instead of the default
Swagger logo.
>> Very flexible stuff.
So that is a complete Web API
with a Swagger endpoint,
with documentation and
I think that's a good module.
>> It's a good place to start,
yeah.
>> Fantastic,
we having an all kinds of fun
here on
Microsoft Virtual Academy.
Stay with us, we've a great
whole series of modules
before this one and after this
one, so be sure to explore.
Thanks so much.
>> All right.