Hey there, welcome back to
this course on ASP.NET Core.
My name is Jeff Fritz.
>> And I'm Scott Hanselman.
>> And in this module,
we're gonna take a look at
building APIs with ASP.NET Core.
>> Yep, we're gonna try,
if we can, without any cuts or
any editing.
>> One shot.
>> To build an API,
we're gonna do it for real.
And if we make a mistake or
if it doesn't compile, we'll
hopefully check each other,
>> We'll fix it.
>> And the goal here to to
build something that is
somewhat non trivial.
We'll build a real web API,
we'll use real web API tools in
order to talk to it We'll show
you Postman, we'll show you
Visual Studio, we're gonna do it
all, of course, in ASP.NET Core.
You've seen us in other modules
talk about Razor Pages.
In this one, we're gonna
be talking about Web APIs.
And what's nice about it
is it's all ASP.NET Core.
So if you have already made
a Razor Page, you're gonna
discover that you can,
in fact, have your Web API's
in your same project as your
Razor Pages, which is nice.
>> Absolutely,
it's the same technology.
You can put the pieces
together that you need to
make the application
with those appropriate LEGO
pieces that snap together.
>> Exactly, all right, so
we're gonna do one that is for
ticketing.
Maria asked me to fit Beyonce
in, in any way possible.
So we'll assume this some kind
of a concert ticketing system.
But that's the general idea.
So I am here in
Visual Studio 2017.
I happen to be using
Visual Studio Community,
which is my preferred version.
So I'm gonna say
File>New>Project.
And I'll just zoom in here.
I've got a choice under
Visual C# for Web.
There's Web Applications using
the full .NET framework,
the .NET framework
that runs on Windows.
We're using, of course, ASP.NET
Core, which runs on Windows, and
also Linux and Mac.
So we'll double click on that.
And that's gonna pop up
a number of choices.
You're gonna want to,
if you're following along,
confirm that you're using
ASP.NET Core 2.0, or 2 1,
or whatever version
is the newest.
You'll noticed if you
pick a older version,
you have fewer choices.
Now these are just building
on top of each other,
this is important.
They are all web applications.
They are all ASP.NET core.
If I pick this one, it's got the
most stuff, and it's meant for
using React and Redux.
I'm not doing Angular.
I am gonna be using
Model-View-Controller
because it's all part
of the larger system.
But I'm not gonna have Razor
Pages in my particular one, so
I just get a little bit smaller,
more of a core,
the essence of my application.
But to be clear,
even if you pick one of these,
you can can either add stuff or
strip things out, can't you?
>> Yeah, these are all, we're
building on the shoulders of
the previous project
templates before them.
>> Exactly.
>> So the API, yes, it doesn't
have Razor formatting for views.
>> But you can add it.
>> The Web Application has those
features added on top of it.
>> Exactly, so for
now we'll pick Web API.
And we'll go and
create that project.
That is going to be an ASP.NET
Core project running on .NET
Core here in Visual Studio 2017.
I wanna open up the solution
explorer, and while that is
getting itself ready we will
just zoom in and take a look.
We have got some default
controllers here.
They gave us
a ValuesController by default.
>> Yeah, very simple controller,
looks and
feels like what we've seen in
older versions of ASP.NET.
>> Doesn't do
anything complicated,
returns a list of strings.
We can just take
a brief look at that.
I'm gonna hit Ctrl+F5.
Ctrl+F5, of course,
starts without debugging,
F5 will start with debugging.
So we're gonna do a quick build,
pop up in that, and
then you can see that
returned those two values,
there's a little bit
of chase in there.
That's these values here.
>> So we returned an array, and
on the way out, Web API and
the API controller format
those as a JSON array
to meet that JSON mime type
that we're delivering in.
>> Now I've got this browser
here, which is Microsoft Edge.
I've also got Chrome.
But when you are making APIs,
it's a good idea to have
a client that's a little
smarter about APIs.
Otherwise, you're just gonna get
either an edge here, black and
white text, or in Chrome you
might have some colored text.
But it's nice, I use Postman,
which is a great tool
that let's me do a GET.
So I'm just gonna go and
paste in that same url.
Notice that I'm doing
it while it's running.
Gotta make sure
that it's running.
And I hit send,
and they send me back this
Pretty printed version.
That was the Raw text
we saw in the browser.
The benefits here is that
I can say it's Pretty, and
then if I didn't get it back the
way I wanted I could hint it in
different directions.
So Postman is gonna be kind
of our browser of choice.
>> Right, it gives us
the ability to add authorization
into our request, or change
headers, and specify different
ways that we want to interact
that are not quite those default
things that the browser
is gonna use every time.
>> Right, right, there ways to
do this in the browser, but
Postman's such
a great API checker.
So you can install that.
We notice, of course,
that this has a 200 OK,
it took no time at all, and
it's really no size at all.
>> Right, that 200 is
a standard HTTP status code.
200 means OK.
There's other status codes that
we'll run into a little bit
later here in the video
where we'll use other status
codes to indicate how
the processing of the API
succeeded or failed.
>> Mm-hm.
All right, so
we are going to make a model for
this that is called tickets,
and we're gonna use
a little database.
But the database we're gonna
use is gonna be an in memory
database.
Because we're not doing
an entity framework course here,
this is a Web API course.
For simplicity's sake, I'm gonna
just use an in memory database.
And I'm gonna make a new class.
And I'm gonna call it, we'll
call it TicketItem, TicketItem.
I should have renamed
that better, TicketItem.
All right, and I know that I'm
gonna use the entity framework, the
Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore
here, so bring that in.
And I'm gonna say zoom in a bit.
Let's think about what
a ticket would have.
Were gonna say prop, tab, tab.
Give it a long for an Id.
Id is good.
Prop, tab, tab, string,
maybe a, oops, I'm not doing so
good with my props there,
Concert, maybe?
>> Sure, that Id might be
like be the ticket number-
>> The ticket number, yeah.
>> That you's see printed
on someones stub.
>> Artist.
>> Of course.
>> And then let's do
a prop that is a Boolean.
I don't know, maybe Available.
This is just kind of
some nonsense for
what we're doing here.
So there's the shape
of a ticket.
That's cool.
And we can put our,
we need a database class,
we can put that anywhere.
I could put it in
the same folder here, or
I could put it in the same file.
But I could also put it
somewhere else, I suppose.
Public class.
I can move it later.
TicketContext.
>> There's actually a Visual
Studio tool that will help
you refactor and move that to
a different file if you'd like.
>> All right, so then we'll
have a constructor for
our ticket context.
And that is gonna
take in some options,
some DbContextOptions for
this TicketContext.
We'll just name them options.
And at this point, it's just
gonna pass them up to the base,
pass them up to the base
library there, options.
So that's gonna go up
to the class above us.
>> The Db context class.
>> Db context,
cuz we are derived from
Db context, exactly.
And then our ticket items,
we're gonna have not just one,
but multiple TicketItem.
And we'll call them TicketItems,
plural, plural. Cool.
>> Does that look legit to you?
Let's take a look.
>> Looks good to me.
>> So we got a ticket item,
little database to put it in and our,
>> Yeah those options,
it's important you receive that
in the constructor, because
that's gonna contain things like
the database connection string,
and the database provider that
it needs to configure for us.
>> Yep, and we don't have to do
anything with it in this case,
we can receive it and
then we pass it along.
>> Yep, just pass it along.
>> Okay, let's take
a look at our startup.
Now, in previous courses and
previous modules,
we talked about how you add
the services that you want.
You add them into your pile and
then you use them or
you set them up to do
whatever you want to do.
So here, of course, we add NVC
which includes our web API and
all those things and
then down here we use it, and
in other videos, we saw that
we added in routing and
other kind of stuff
that you can add, but
I think the default routes will
be okay for what we're doing.
Now, on top of this NVC service
and this pile of services,
this collection of services,
we're gonna go and
add in that DbContext
that we made there.
We gonna say hey there's this
TicketContext out there and
remember those options.
We're gonna go and
make a little setting there,
we're gonna say use and
you notice here I wanna say
use in memory database.
But it doesn't show up because
InMemoryDatabase is an add on,
okay, it's a thing that you
would go and get later.
Now here it says well we don't
have the InMemoryDatabase and
nothing is available,
maybe it's over here in
entity framework core
in that new space.
So it will go and
add that namespace, that
namespace show it up at the top.
So I go back down here and
I can hit Control
dot again and seeing that I,
there you go.
InMemoryDatabase and
we'll give it a name TicketList.
OK and then we close it and
close it.
>> Yep.
>> And then we're good, okay?
And I don't think we need
to bring out models cuz I
don't think we're
gonna use them here.
So that should work to see if
that compiles looks like it did.
So, clearly we can ship it.
[LAUGH]
>> Absolutely, we're done.
>> We've done nothing.
>> We can ship to values.
>> All right.
Now we've got our ticket, we've
told it we're gonna use an in
memory database for
our ticket context.
We can add a controller so
I'm gonna right click, and
I'll say add.
Now before I said add new item,
and then picked from the list.
Here we're gonna say
add controller and
this is an interesting one.
There's a bunch of different
scaffolding choices you can use,
you can do like your
MVC Controllers for
your Razor in your html.
You can do an API Controller,
now here we've got Empty but
I've also got one called
Entity Framework.
I could cheat, couldn't I?
>> Yeah.
>> Not, cheat.
Cheat is not a right word,
I could fast forward time.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And
say, Scaffold it all I would
make a complete crawd.
Create, read, update, delete.
Do you want me to do that, or
are we going to build
this from scratch?
>> Let's do this by hand just so
we can walk through and talk
a little bit more towards what
each one of the methods are, and
how you need to interact
with those items.
>> Okay, so we'll do that.
We'll make a new empty
controller, so it's going to go
think about that and we'll
call it the ticket controller.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, because it's firing
up the scaffolding system,
this will just take a moment and
also want to make sure that the
project can build after effect.
This is a little bit slower than
just and saying add new item and
making a text file cuz right
now, it's looking at my
system and if it was gonna
scout for a bunch of stuff.
>> It's adding
in those features-
>> Mm-hm.
>> That weren't
previously in there.
If you were to go and
add another controller
at this point,
those features have already
been added to this project.
>> Yep.
>> It doesn't need to re-add
them at this point.
>> Mm-hm.
This is interesting.
Here is says, well I'm gonna
assume this is a route at route
api/Ticket, so
it's described in the URL.
Little tip here for you though,
you could also go like this and
that's saying whatever the name
of that controller is.
>> That thing before controller
in the name of the class.
>> Right, so the word controller
in that case is a well known
name, magic name but
I could also make this Foo, so
api/Foo would go to
ticket controller.
In this case api/Ticket or
I could hard code api/Ticket, so
you got a lot of choices there.
Routing and attribute routing
gives you a lot of choices there
and then this seems
pretty clear.
Produces application/json,
makes some json.
>> We're forcing
the mime type that
we're gonna be interacting with.
We're, if we didn't use that,
it could actually adapt and
respond appropriately if it
requests xml, instead of json.
>> So we could even
remove that then and
possibly return xml
instead of json?
>> Yes.
>> We'll leave it there for now.
>> Sure.
>> Okay, so we're inside of
our ticket controller and
our ticket controller
is gonna need that database
context, that ticket context.
I'll just name it
ticket context,
we'll make it private and we'll
say public TicketController and
that'll pass in the database
context and then at which point,
as I like to say,
I will squirrel that away.
And then for the purposes of
testing, this is just for
testing, but this is
something to do because we're
using an in memory database.
We'll say,
hey if there's not any ticket
items in there at all,
if the count of those tickets is
zero, let's just throw one in.
So that way,
when we first start the app up,
it'll have something.
This is cheesy.
There are other ways to do this.
>> Sure.
>> But for what we're doing,
I think it's fine.
>> Well yeah.
We could've also included
there a test, if this is
the development environment,
then add a ticket so that we
have something to work with.
>> Mm-hm.
That is a good point.
And then, so we're just saying
if there's nothing there,
add something in.
>> Sure.
>> Probably not something you
want to do in the constructor,
but not too bad.
Okay, all right, now do we
have any ticket controller?
Does that look good?
>> Yep, we have
a TicketController that is gonna
start up.
If there aren't any tickets
currently in the database,
we're gonna create one for
the Beyonce concert.
>> So we should make a get all.
>> Sure, so that we can
actually see those tickets that
are in the database.
>> Because right now,
it doesn't really do anything.
There's no way to get anything.
>> No.
>> Okay, so we're going to
go and make a public and
it's going to be a list or
IEnumerable of ticket items.
>> A collection that
we can through.
>> A list of.
We say IEnumberable because
it's going to go forward only,
and we'll just call it GetAll(),
and
we'll do the least that
it can possibly do.
It'll say
TicketItems.ToList(); and
as I recall I think if you
wanna be super correct,
was there not an order tracking,
do you remember what this was?
I did this yesterday, there's
a little tip that you can give
your context on whether or
not you wanna do order tracking.
I think it was context.
Change tracker
>> I think it's change tracker.
>> I don't think it's change tracker
>> You can Disable it.
>> I'll leave that,
actually I just want to
know this for myself.
For a brief moment here,
let's take a look at this.
Because basically if you're
just returning some stuff,
in this case you're
returning just some tickets,
you're not gonna
be changing them.
You don't need to be
taking any time and
wasting anytime on
watching them for changes.
So, yesterday when we did this.
Take a look here in my
pages I believe I put it in
index there you go,
customers as no tracking.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, let's see if that's
available so back over here.
I'll say
TicketItems.AsNoTracking.
>> Keep typing it.
There's a extension there
that you're missing from
Entity Framework.
>> Okay,
is that what's going on?
>> Mm-hm.
AsNoTracking is a method.
>> Okay, and
where is AsNoTracking located?
>> There you go.
>> EntityFrameworkCore,
there you go.
So we hover over that and it
says, returns a new query, and
this is important,
where the change tracker
won't track the entities,
meaning it's not going to
watch for them to be modified.
>> Right.
>> Now,
if you find adding
that is annoying,
the other option is that
you flip it, right?
So you change query tracking
behavior to have this disabled
all the time, and then you
turn it on when you need to.
>> Yes.
Okay, not necessary, but
certainly never hurts to be
a little bit, a little premature
optimization never hurt anybody.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Until it totally did.
Cool, so this might work.
>> It might because we're,
we've named our method
with the keyword get.
>> What would then doing this,
HttpGet do?
So by adding the attribute
HttpGet above it,
it's explicitly telling
the API handlers inside of NVC
that we're handling the HTTP GET
verb with this method.
We could also specify
with that HttpGet
the route that we wanna listen
on if we wanted to listen
somewhere different
than the default.
>> Right, okay, so here.
There we go.
>> There you go.
>> So I just hit /api/Ticket.
And then we got back
our JSON again.
And this is our raw JSON.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Here's our Pretty JSON.
Doing that from, and
you notice what I'm doing is I'm
hitting Ctrl F5, in this case,
I'm ignoring what
the browser says and
I'm going back over to Postman.
>> Sure, the browsers
still showing that values
controller you were working on.
>> I could also change
the default URL.
Right now, it's showing up as
the default is slash value.
I could also, if I wanted to,
basically tell
Visual Studio that there is
a browser called Postman.
>> Yes.
>> So I could go in here and
add postman as a browser and
then try to open it
from there as well.
>> Absolutely.
>> Okay, All right, so
that's all of tickets.
>> One more thing that I wanted
to look at when we're in
postman.
So check it out, even though
we only set a value for
the Beyonce concert, we got
an ID of one because it's an ID.
Entity framework sees that has
an auto incrementing primary key
and it generated a number for
us.
>> So entity framework
gave us that one.
We did not make that one.
>> Exactly, where those default
values for the artist property
and available property were
generated as just null and
false, because those
are the default values.
>> For those data types.
>> Right, they came along for
the ride cuz we
returned that object.
>> Okay, that makes sense.
Hopefully, people will forgive
me as they did yesterday for
not putting the accent on
the e in Beyonce, all right.
Cool, now let's do a GetByID.
>> Sure,
I wanna get a specific ticket.
>> All right, so
this one's gonna be public.
And just like before, when we
did this with Razor Pages,
we have IActionResult.
We're gonna say GetById.
We'll pass in long id.
We don't know where that's being
passed in from though yet.
We haven't figured out how
does this ID get populated.
Now initially,
it's gonna warn me.
Well this is bad.
You're gonna think
you made a mistake.
It's just saying you have
not yet returned a value.
We're gonna say, go get
a ticket, borrow a ticket,
context., pull them out
of the TicketItems and
then we'll say FirstOrDefault,
where that ticket such
that that ticket ID is the same
as the ID that we then pass in.
So we're gonna go and find the
ticket item that matches the one
that we just passed in.
>> And important to use
FirstOrDefault because if
it doesn't find one, we'll get a
default ticket that is null and
doesn't contain anything.
>> Right, and
then we'll check for that null.
If the ticket is null, now is
interesting, what you wanna do
is you're thinking from
a pseudo code perspective.
I wanna return a 404, right?
I wanna figure out
how to change my
HTTP response to indicate a 404,
as opposed to a 200 Okay.
>> Right, that 404 indicates
that this object wasn't
found, right?
If this was a file system,
there isn't a file with
that name here on disk.
>> Right, and
that's a good reminder.
If you think about your 200
series is mostly things are OK.
>> Yeah.
>> Your 300 series is
something has changed, and
you need to do
something about it.
Your 400 series is, and
I like to say it this,
it's probably your fault.
And your 500 series is,
it's probably my fault.
And by that, I mean 400 is
don't know where that is.
I'm pretty much sure it was you.
You gave me the wrong URL,
couldn't find it.
500 is something horrible
happened on the server.
So you could separate this.
This is client stuff, and
this is server side stuff.
So one of the great things
about web APIs when you
write them with ASP.NET core
is a whole bunch of cool
things like not found
a helper functions.
I can say, look not found.
And if I hover it, it returns
StatusCodes.Status404NotFound,
which is an enumeration.
I go and say, StatusCodes.,
see look at all that.
>> I don't wanna
remember all that.
>> No.
>> Plus I don't want to
dig into it anew.
So we've got a nice little
helper, return not found,
does the right thing.
That implies,
well it doesn't imply,
it is-
>> It is.
>> A 404.
>> But
if you need that granularity for
those other status codes,
they're there for you.
>> You've got it, good point.
If I did find it, well then
I want to return that, and
that is an object
that I just found.
So then I'm gonna return
an ObjectResult, and
I'll put a ticket in there, and
that ObjectResult is gonna
come back with a 200 and
say hey, here's that object
that I asked for, okay?
Where's that ID come from?
Up here we said get,
we're very explicit.
>> Yeah.
>> We need to give
some hints cuz we wanna
know what our URL's look like,
dont we?
So we know it's gonna be a Get,
don't we?
>> Absolutely.
>> We open that Get up, and we
say, we're gonna pull id out of
the URL and then we can also
change the name if we want to.
This is kinda cool.
You could say ticket slash
this or ticket slash that.
I'm gonna go ahead and
change this.
We'll just say it so we can.
I'm gonna say Name = GetTicket.
And this is showing you
that you can make it so
the URL is different
from the function name.
>> Actually that name should
be inside the parenthesis.
>> Pardon me, thank you.
>> All right, so we say
HttpGet id, Name = Get Ticket.
Zoom out, let's hit Ctrl+F5 and
see if we can
access that method.
>> All right.
>> Cuz we know that we have by
default one item
to beyonce ticket.
>> Mm-hm, okay.
>> All right, so before we did
this, which was api/Ticket.
>> Right,
return all of my tickets.
>> Okay.
>> So now we know
there's just the one.
>> Okay, and
here I said GetTicket.
You think it's Ticket.
>> There you go.
>> There it is.
So what is the term GetTicket
then in that context?
>> GetTicket is actually
the name of the route that we've
create, because we're
using the HTTP GET verb.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And we're specifying,
we're adding another route onto
the default route table,
defining it right here,
next to the method that we
want to respond to that route.
>> Okay, so is that necessary?
>> Nope, it's optional.
>> And that is there so
that I can give it a name and
then manipulate it later,
refer to it by name.
>> Exactly, so if you were
to pass a reference to this
somewhere into maybe
a JavaScript file, you wanna be
able to say, you know what,
use the URL, I'd get ticket.
>> Or to generate a URL based on
that route, now I have it named.
Now you have a name that you can
easily reference and remember.
>> All right, cool, so
here we said api/Ticket
where this 1,
that's that ID, okay?
>> That template that we're-
>> That template.
>> Trying to capture.
>> Exactly, and
that worked great.
And we got that back, okay?
So that works out pretty nicely.
Now how do we create new
tickets with an API, Scott?
>> All right, let's do that.
All right, so
I've got my notes here.
Well, actually, one thing
that I do want to show,
we're in Postman but
let's take a moment and
let's look at this in
the other browsers.
Because you might not
want to use Postman,
maybe you don't have Postman,
let's just take a look briefly.
We're in Microsoft Edge, okay.
I can go and say dot dot
dot F12 developer tools.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
And I can look at the network,
hit refresh, can come
down here we can see it was a
200 We can see how long it took.
>> It was JSON that it returned?
>> Yeah, we can see that
content type, you can go in and
filter based on those things.
If I go over here,
we can see the request headers.
Notice that it said I can
take pretty much anything.
Return to JSON.
You can see that Kestrel,
the name of our little
web server there.
And there's powered-by ASP.NET.
If I do the same thing
in Chrome There's
my JSON And I'm gonna say
More Tools > Developer Tools.
And hit Refresh again.
Similar kind of thing,
real similar developer tools,
your request, your response,
and all that kind of stuff.
So you can, to a point,
manipulate web APIs.
I like Postman.
Use what makes you happy, but be
aware that F12 tools are great
basically in all the browsers,
and you can enjoy those.
Now you said,
how do we make one?
Because right now we just have
the auto-generated Beyonce one.
>> Yeah, let's put somebody else
in the seats there for Beyonce.
>> Let's mix it up.
Lets be for everyone.
So lets do another one that
returns an IActionResult, and
this one will be called Create.
And it's gonna take
in a TicketItem.
Just like ID,
we haven't decided where
it's coming from yet, okay?
>> Okay.
>> And we'll say if (ticket ==
null), that'll be a problem.
So that'll probably
a BadRequest.
Remember, we talked about
these different versions.
What is that?
That's a 400.
>> There you go.
That's the your made a mistake.
>> Your fault.
Not my fault.
That's not a 500.
Not a server error, that's,
you messed up, not me.
Context, you,
meaning the client, to be clear.
We'll go and add that ticket.
And then I'm gonna go and
say, SaveChanges.
And this is a great one,
I like this,
this is a convenient
little method here.
You ready for this?
>> Okay.
>> CreatedAtRoute, GetTicket.
This answers my first
question which is the,
why would I name a route?
>> There you go.
>> Like that, and
then I would then pass in
the shape of this object
that I just created,
this is kind of
an anonymous object there.
And I say I made one, and
here's my little projected ID,
and then I pass in
the one we just made.
>> So
the first two arguments of that
method, are building a route.
We had the GetTicket route.
>> [CROSSTALK]
>> It's building a URL.
>> Exactly, yes,
we had the GetTicket route,
we need to specify the ID to
be passed into that method.
So, you have your object
defining that and
then the actual object
we're returning.
>> So, let's be real clear, you
could do something like this.
And you'd have to build
this up yourself.
All right.
>> Yeah.
>> But now-
>> With the appropriate status code.
>> You need the status code.
You need to go and make the URL.
What if you change
your URL names?
What if you move things around?
What if you wanna rename
things in a different way?
If you want to do that,
do you really want
to be in the business of
string-concatenating URLs?
>> Yeah, let's get
rid of those magic strings
as much as possible.
>> So, I like that you
referred to it as a route,
which is more abstract.
The URL is underneath that.
Yeah.
>> That's good.
>> I try to avoid working with
URLs directly when I'm writing
my asp.net.
>> As much as we
are in the business of
concatenating strings, let's
try to pretend that we're not.
>> Yeah, let something
else manage those strings.
>> Yeah, and that's where we
use our framework like this.
So the only thing that I think
we're missing here is the,
where has this come from?
All right.
>> Yeah, so, before,
we actually,
we put it on the query string.
I don't think we can put on
the query string on the URL
a full ticket.
>> You probably don't want to.
>> No.
>> You could theoretically have
name equals value name equal
value, a disassembled ticket
on a very long query string,
but really, it's the body.
It's the body of the post.
We want to put the ticket
inside the body of the post.
And then we want to have this-
>> Object
>> De-serialized
>> Yes
>> It's rehydrated-
>> Converted from the JSON string
>> The JSON, exactly.
>> And you were mentioning
this should be a post.
We should probably
put a URL on this,
a verb on it to indicate that
this should handle a post.
>> Good post, good point.
Good point, good post.
We said HttpGet before,
we will say post this time.
We don't wanna
accidentally make it so
someone could hit
/ticket/Create with a get.
>> Correct, yeah.
>> And have it do anything.
So let's do this,
let's put a break point here and
let's start a debugging session.
>> Very good.
>> Equivalent of pressing F5.
So it's still of course going
to /api/values which is fine.
>> Yeah.
>> We've already proven
that we can go and
see our Beyonce ticket here.
I'm gonna cheat and
I'm gonna copy that.
>> Okay.
>> Cuz I wanna be doing a post
of the opposite of that, right?
>> Sure.
>> So what I wanna do here, and
you can correct me if I'm wrong.
Is I'm gonna post to api/ticket
Not a get, but a post.
>> Yep.
>> In the body,
we're gonna have This JSON.
So I told it we're
putting JSON in the body,
I don't think I
need to say an ID.
>> Nope,
it's gonna generate that for us.
>> Okay, who's in concert?
You just blanked
on all musicians.
>> [LAUGH]
>> Coldplay.
>> There you go [LAUGH]
>> Well let's just do this,
let's just be haters,
it's Beyonce with Nickelback.
[LAUGH]
>> I love Canadians.
>> There you go,
what's it called?
>> Rush.
>> There you go, that's, I've
no idea who that is, all right.
>> There are Canadians
that are now-
>> Are they Canadian?
>> Very.
>> Okay, so
we're gonna post this body.
Actually I'll make it true
as well as why not, right?
Okay and just before I hit send
I wanna just come back over here
and make sure that I've
got a break point there.
>> Yup.
>> Because I'm hoping that I
will hit send then it will pop
over into that break point.
>> No problem.
>> No problem, you confident?
>> You got this, yeah.
>> A hundred percent.
All right, look at that.
So I'm gonna zoom in here,
I'm gonna hover over ticket.
>> It's a ticket item.
>> Look at that.
This is another little tip I
was talking to Maria
about yesterday.
You could this.
>> Yeah.
>> So we'll keep that around and
that makes little easier
to do our debugging.
>> Well if you don't want it
there hanging over your code,
that's actually the same
things that you might see down
in the locals window
at the bottom.
>> That's a good point come down
here and there it is there.
All right.
So just to be clear,
if we go back to post banner,
right now it's loading
because the request,
it's a long-running request,
right?
It's never actually finished.
>> Yeah, we're blocking it
right now with our debugger.
>> Let's just go ahead and
continue so
that this finishes, all right.
There's our returned.
>> Right.
Look at what came back.
We created the object and
returned it all in one request.
Our new object that we created-
>> That was here.
We said CreatedAtRoute and then
passed in that object value,
got it back.
>> Right, and the created add is
a different status code, right?
See that 201 created?
>> Right, so look at this.
When you said CreatedAtRoute,
what you got back
was a new location.
You got back the location
of this new thing.
Cuz when you're making a web API
it's all about being restful.
REST, Representational
State Transfer.
And basically if
I uploaded a GIF,
I want the URL of
the GIF where it is now.
I just uploaded a new concert.
Tell me the location
of that new thing.
>> It's telling you
the location as a header.
It's not actually
navigated you to that.
>> Right,
cuz it's on me to go and decide.
So then I could come up here and
then do a GET.
Okay and let's, oops.
There in our body.
And there, I just got a GET
from that new location,
to prove that it
is in fact there.
>> There's still tickets
available for that Rush event.
>> I don't know why.
>> Beyonce was sold out.
>> Beyonce's
completely sold out.
It's funny how that works.
Yeah, cool.
That worked really well.
So then the next thing I might
wanna do would be to update it,
okay?
>> Sure, we sold the last
ticket in that Rush event.
>> Right.
And when we are doing CRUD,
right?
That's Create Read
Update Delete, and
we are mapping that
to HTTP Verbs.
Create is usually a POST,
read is usually a GET, Update is
usually a PUT and delete is
surprisingly enough, a DELETE.
>> Naming's hard.
>> Naming is hard.
But that's how we mapped
CRUD to HTTP Verbs.
So then we're gonna
do an update.
>> Yeah,
PGPD is not a cool acronym.
>> No, that's not
a cool acronym at all.
So let's try this.
We shall make a public
IActionResult.
Now we're doing this manually.
I still think there's value
in doing that, but before,
we did see that we could
potentially have the system
scaffold this out.
So it's good to know
how to do it once.
You learn how to drive
a manual shift car once, and
then you get
an automatic shift car.
You don't get to drive the
automatic until you learn how to
drive stick.
>> I like still
driving my manual car.
>> I take the bus.
FromBody, right.
So here we're gonna go and
do an update.
We're passing in the new updated
item along with the id of
the thing we want to update.
So we're saying here's the Rush
tickets, that's number two.
>> Right.
>> With what it
should look like now.
>> Mm-hm.
>> Okay?
All right,
now we gotta do the usual.
If ticket equals null, or maybe
that the ticket that you passed
in doesn't actually match the ID
that you want me to change,
that's not cool.
>> Trying to sabotage
the content there.
>> Can't do that,
that's a bad request.
So not cool, all right?
Now, let's go and
get the ticket there,
might be more than one ticket.
But let's go and
say var tic = _context.
And then we're gonna
go just like before,
we're gonna say FirstOrDefault.
Oops, FirstOrDefault.
T such that, that id equals
the id that you passed in.
>> Now here we can't do
the turn off of the tracking,
because we are actually gonna
track the changes on this one.
>> Yeah, that's a good point.
So here we're gonna go and
make sure that that
ticket Is not null.
If it is null, then we're going
to NotFound(); that, okay?
So that's not found.
Now we make changes.
So, multiple ways that you
could potentially do this.
I'm gonna do just what they call
left hand, right hand code.
This is simple enough that
it's not a huge deal.
I could do different
bits of work here.
I could compare things,
be more sophisticated.
There are mapping tools and
mapping systems that would
go and do that for me.
If I had dozens of items or-
>> Properties.
>> That you had to map.
>> Deep, but for now, we're
gonna go and say, all right
_context.TicketItems.Update with
the new ticket.
_context.SaveChanges.
And then because an update
doesn't really do anything,
we're just gonna say,
NoContentResult();.
So we did it, and
we're done, and it worked.
>> Just gonna acknowledge
that we finished.
>> We finished, and it's cool,
and I think that is,
I think it's a 201 but it's not
a 200 It's just gonna look.
Yep, we're cool, it worked..
All right, let's give it try,
and this is gonna be with a PUT.
And let's actually try
it with a debug session.
So we're up and running.
First, and this is kinda cool,
you can go back over
your histories.
And you can like replay stuff.
So here we'll replay our,
Rush creation.
>> Yeah.
>> And this is another nice
thing about Postman and
tools like it,
is that you can go and
create collections and then kind
of do unit testing on that.
Now here's what we're gonna do.
Rush, it says
available equals true.
Let's go and do a PUT.
Here's gonna be the body.
We will say that it
is now sold out.
So we're gonna PUT
to that location,
and I think what would we say?
>> We have to specify the id.
>> Do we have to say id?
It depends on how we wrote it,
we did.
>> Actually you know what?
>> No, we did not actually.
And you know what else we did?
We didn't put any of the route
information at the top.
>> We forgot a route.
>> All right, this is good.
>> So
where you were saying earlier,
that's actually a GET because
it doesn't have the verb on it.
>> That would have been a GET
had we not done anything,
good point.
So we will say put with the id,
then do we need this?
>> No, we don't need
a name on this one.
>> Don't think we need a name.
But that's PUT with an id, okay?
>> There you go.
>> All right.
F5.
Launch.
Back out here, replay my post.
Available true,
now we're gonna do a PUT.
Available false.
>> So what came back?
What's down there?
>> So
I didn't get a break point.
Unsupported media type.
All right, that's great.
So this is really useful.
So see it says
unsupported media type?
When I said PUT and
I clicked raw,
I did not tell it it was JSON.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay?
That would change the headers.
Cuz in the headers,
by saying it's JSON,
we say the content type
of this thing is JSON.
So I pushed raw text edit and it
said what it should have said.
400, remember the 400 series
of errors are my fault?
>> Yep.
>> Unsupported media type.
>> Looked at that text and
didn't know how to
rehydrate a ticket.
>> And what's nice is that
I didn't write that code,
I didn't write any
code to do that.
It figured it out on its own.
>> Yep.
>> Send.
Here we go.
>> All right.
>> We are in update number two.
Here is the new ticket.
Available false.
Let's go and do some stepping.
Step over, step over.
Found the ticket.
Now here is the available
true and the available false.
Now it's falsely updated, and
we return the no content result.
Let's return back to Postman.
And again,
as I suspected, a 200.
But it's a 204, which means it's
okay, because it's a 200 series.
04, no content.
That's great.
So at this point,
we're almost done.
Let's go back.
Let's bang out a delete.
And take a little break.
>> [CROSSTALK] Final
part of that, correct.
>> We'll take a break
cuz good for us.
This time,
since we know what we're doing,
we'll put HttpDelete
right at the top.
And I'll say public
IActionResultDelete(long id).
>> We need to specify that id's
gonna come in off a route.
>> Okay, good point.
So we add that here.
Id.
>> There you go.
>> Thank you, sir.
And then we will say, var tics
=, pull it out of the context,
get it out of there,
FirstOrDefault.
Oops, get my little
IntelliSense there.
FirstOrDefault t
such that t.Id= id.
>> Yeah, there you go.
>> And then, again, if I wanted
to make this a little simpler.
You notice that I've done
this a couple of times now.
It might be nice to move that
into another location, or
have someone else be
responsible for that.
Maybe that would be
a factory pattern.
There's a half dozen different
ways that you could write that
code.
As well as hiding
this not found,
cuz we've been a little
bit repetitive, right?
Wouldn't you say?
>> Absolutely.
>> Now, this one's easy.
Go and get that ticket item,
and we're just gonna say,
remove this one.
And then, once we've removed it.
>> Don't need the TicketItems,
they're just
context.SaveChanges.
>> Thank you sir, SaveChanges().
And then, again,
another return NoContentResult.
>> Awesome, fabulous.
>> And in the interest of time,
when I write code,
I don't always write code.
When I do though, I immediately
deploy it to production.
So assume that that works.
All right, so
there, and not too bad,
we've made a ticket controller.
We have a little bit of code
here that adds Beyonce,
because all concerts
should have Beyonce.
We've got our GetAll,
our GetById, our Create,
our Update, finally our Delete.
All in this case,
using Entity Framework and
an in-memory database.
But it could easily be moved
into a Postgres, or SQL, or
MySQL, or
whatever makes you happy.
>> Absolutely.
>> Yeah, and
let's take a short break, and
then we'll come back and add
a little documentation for this.
>> Sounds good.
>> All right, hope you
join us here on
Microsoft Virtual Academy.