Hey, welcome back
to the ASP.NET Core
course here on
Microsoft Virtual Academy.
My name is Jeff Fritz.
>> I'm Jon Galloway.
>> And we're gonna take
a look at actually making
this stuff into production.
Let's publish.
>> It's always funny, we talk
about building web apps and
let's actually put it
out on the web now.
[LAUGH]
>> Yeah, let's do it.
>> So I'm starting with this
very simple File>New Project,
and I'm doing this
with no authentication,
keeping it really lightweight.
>> Sure.
>> This stuff works,
deploying with migrations and
Entity Framework and
databases and all that but
it takes a bit longer, and
I wanna just show the really
quick simple path here.
So I could actually,
this shows here,
publish information,
I've [LAUGH] got an app,
I haven't even done anything
with it yet locally.
>> And it's right there
on the welcome page.
>> Right, so [LAUGH] now I could
also, if I want to publish,
I can right-click here and
do right-click Publish, right?
So we should talk as I'm
publishing about what this
actually means.
Normally, You wanna set
something up when you're doing
more, like here actually I've
got to reenter my credentials.
I don't know if you wanna
talk about the whole idea,
like is it a good idea
to right-click publish?
>> Sure, I mean, right,
when you right-click in
publish in application,
it's really a one off thing.
It's not something that you
wanna do every time there's
a change that you're
making to production space
because it's not repetitive.
It's not something that you can
repeat and be guaranteed you're
gonna get the exact same
configuration every time.
You may wanna be deploying from
a continuous integration system,
something like
Visual Studio Team Services, or
perhaps you wanna deploy
directly from GitHub.
You can do these things with the
features available on Azure, but
this is great for getting that
first deployment up and running.
Or maybe you wanna deploy to
a test area or a deployment slot
out there, so that you can
work with that directly.
>> Exactly, yep.
So kind of my favorite way that
I usually will work is I'll work
in a repo kind of right away,
I'll get a repo going.
You can do free private repos
out on VSTS or visualstudio.com
and then you can get free
public repos on GitHub.
So between the two of those,
I'm covered for a free repo use.
>> Absolutely.
>> And so I will go through and
configure that and
then configure Get Deployment,
and it does that CI Deployment.
So every time I do a push,
it's going to automatically
deploy from source control.
>> Yep, update Azure with
all the latest bits and
hopefully, you have
some tests and
things in line there to verify
that it is proper to deploy.
>> Yep, but as we're talking
about for a quick, hey, I wanna
try this out, I wanna see this
running on the public Internet.
I want to share it with maybe
I'm developing this site for
somebody and
I want them to get a look at it.
Here it is, so
this is a live URL, so
this is up on the Internet here.
>> It took us maybe a minute,
and
you can share this with
a customer, that's great.
>> Yep, so and especially if
you've got MSDN, or if people
you're developing with have
MSDN, if your shop has MSDN,
this is great to use your
included MSDN credits.
>> Right,
your Azure subscription.
>> Azure subscription, and
set up testing, deployment,
and all that kind of stuff.
So that's kind of a quick
look at [LAUGH] very
quick deployment.
So here's the site running,
and one of the cool features,
now that it's running
in app service,
is that I can use App Insights.
Okay, so-
>> What does App Insights do?
>> So App Insights profiles my
application as it's running in
production, and
it tells me all kinds of things,
statistics about how
fast it's running.
Things that are bottlenecks, any
errors helps me diagnose things.
>> Okay.
>> And what's cool is that
used to take several steps to
configure that.
Now you actually don't have to
make any code changes in your
application.
>> Terrific.
>> You just go up into Azure and
when you go to your site, it'll
show a thing at the top that
will say, hey, do you wanna
turn on App Insights?
So it actually looks
just like this.
In the dashboard,
right here on a deployed app,
this is gonna say, hey you don't
have App Insights turned on,
click this and
we'll configure it for you.
So I'm actually gonna show
you a running website
because there's not much to
show you on this website,
we just deployed it, there's
not much to profile there.
So I've actually got a website I
deployed over this past weekend,
we'll take a look at it.
But what's really neat here
is I don't have to make
any code changes to
enable App Insights.
It's able to inject this
directly into my application as
it's running.
There's no code
modifications at all.
So I'm gonna be showing you some
things on this .NET Foundation
website.
This is an ASP.NET Core
application, I just deployed it.
And I actually used that
App Insights to help kind of
troubleshoot and see what things
are running first and slow, and
that kind of stuff.
So when I click through on this,
I'll click on monitor
App Insights and it'll show,
if I click through this will
show the actual application.
And I need to make sure that
I'm picking a time range.
If you're not seeing
information out there,
it may be that you're filtering
down on the wrong time range.
So here I'm gonna filter for
the last seven days so I can see
kinda what I was looking
at over the past weekend.
And so here immediately,
I can see some neat things.
Like for instance, it's got an
App Map, and it's actually going
through and discovering what
kind of things that I'm doing.
So here in this case,
there's not a whole lot but
let's say I was calling out
to a lot of other services or
using databases to profile, etc,
it could help diagnose that.
It also helps me to see what
kind of users are looking.
As I was kind of going through,
this is actually saying during
the past 24, let me expand
it to that seven days again.
And here we can see this is
what the users were looking at,
where they were, this was
me testing a home on Microsoft Edge.
But we can go through and
look at what all kinds
of stuff about them.
And then I can
actually go in and
see what sort of requests
were being called overall and
what things were running
faster or slower.
See you'll notice here
if I dig in to this and
look at what sort of request
I have, I can see things like
common properties,
common request and things.
I can also see that for
instance, I've got a lot of
request to this holder JS and
this is actually something
that's generating some
thumbnails for me.
And I can get an idea of like,
well, was it running quickly and
if not, is there maybe something
that I could do to speed it up?
So this is all great profiling
information that I can get.
And if I really wanna
dig deeper into it,
I can go even into analytics,
and this'll let me run queries.
And so here I can go in,
I can say okay,
what sort of things happened
over this day time range, and
I can really dig in and generate
some advanced charts and stuff.
Again, I did no co changes at
all for this, this is just
something that's built in
directly, so that's really cool.
All right, so
now we've looked at all that and
we're going to next move on and
take a look at Docker.
One of the things that Docker
offers me is it's kind of
repeatable package that includes
everything about my application.
>> It's like taking a snapshot
of your application
that you can easily
stand up anywhere.
>> Yep, so here I did right
click Add>Docker Support,
and here I have a choice
of operating system.
This is a bit of
a mind blower here,
I'm actually gonna target Linux,
so I'm using
a Linux Docker container,
running on my Windows machine.
And it's gonna package it up and
do that all automatically for
me.
So some of the neat
things it does here for
me is it creates this Dockerfile
and this Dockerfile is kind of
a recipe of here's what's needed
to package up my application.
So this is saying take this,
the microsoft/aspnetcore
version 2.0 Docker container.
>> Mm-hm.
>> And then it says,
grab my source, and
it has a working directory
on the container and
it just copies that code over.
It exposes port 80, and
then at the end here it says,
this is how to actually run it.
If we look here, it's actually
done a few other things for
me, there's Docker file ignored.
These are things that you
normally don't want published
out to your Docker file.
>> Right.
>> There's a couple,
there's also Docker compose.
If I wanna have multiple
different things,
if I wanna have maybe some
microservices or whatever.
And then this,
docker compose ci, is used for
the actual build process.
So we don't actually need to
deploy this stuff out onto our,
we want a very tight,
lightweight docker container
when we actually deploy it.
This is used in Build, but
not used in my final
Docker container.
>> Right, this, we're actually
gonna expose the source code to
this so that our build operation
actually takes place inside of
another Docker container.
So we get that sanitary
clean room for the build.
So we get to the exact same
build every time and then we're
gonna output that information
into another Docker container.
And that's what we will
package up and turn into our
image that will create copies
of our web application from.
>> Cool, I wanna show just
one other thing here.
I wanna actually run this
application in Docker,
locally, and
I'm gonna set a breakpoint.
So I've got a breakpoint set.
So I'm actually gonna be
debugging into the Docker
container and then I've added
something into my index view
that shows the operating
system version.
>> Okay.
>> So then I hit run and
I haven't done anything
special in this application.
I have installed
Docker beforehand and
there's stuff in the Docks
about how to do that.
>> So our start debug button
flipped from saying either our
project name or IS express, and
it now said Docker because
starting it in Docker.
And passing control back to me,
in Microsoft Edge.
>> Yeah,
now here's a crazy thing.
I actually hit a breakpoint so
I'm debugging.
I'm able to debug,
I can do edit and continue,
all that kind of stuff.
>> So you're debugging
in application you wrote
on Windows,
hosting on a Linux container and
exposing a debugging
back to Windows.
>> Back, yes, exactly,
back into Visual Studio.
So it's possible for me to,
right at the beginning of my
project, build it on Docker.
It's not gonna slow me down as
I develop the whole way through
and I know when I'm done,
I can just deploy it and
I've been testing it
all the way along.
Now here's the final little
mind blower, I hit Continue and
we'll see the application
come up and
you see way up in that corner
there, here's the OS version.
So this is running in a Unix.
It's a Linux container, and this
is running, I'm building this in
Visual Studio,
testing with a Docker container.
>> All on Windows 10.
>> Yep.
>> Nice.
>> All right, so
a bit of a whirlwind here,
but we went through looking
at File> New Project,
deployed it to Azure.
>> Yep.
>> Played with App Insights.
>> App Insights.
>> And I just kind of
poked around a bit at it.
There's quite a bit more in
the documentation
of what you can do.
And if you've got a running
website, I've used that so
many times to diagnose exactly
what's going wrong, or
what could speed up.
>> Yeah, there's logging
information in there that
you could dig into,
that is being output as
the application is running, so.
>> Yeah, and then finally,
we looked at Docker and
literally just right clicks,
add Docker support and
then hit a breakpoint and
checked out, yes indeed,
it is running in
a Linux container.
>> So you showed us that there
is a continuous integration
file in there that we
can use with VSTS so
that we can generate our
images as we build each time.
>> Exactly.
>> Cool.
>> All right, let's stop there.
>> Thanks so much for
joining us here on
Microsoft Virtual Academy.